<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/misc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 7 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wolf&#34;&gt;Wolf!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with this redone page! I was originally just going to fill in the existing line work digitally, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too sure with the result, so I redrew Wolf. It looks &lt;em&gt;SO&lt;/em&gt; much better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-following-changes-were-made-to-page-7&#34;&gt;The following changes were made to page 7:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew panel 1 (kept the same glow lines).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colored whole page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew text boxes and updated text box fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated sound effect in panel 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the new page 7 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;Next week, I look forward to doing something a little different than the usual,&lt;/strong&gt; so don&amp;rsquo;t forget to come back and check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-the-chase&#34;&gt;Back to the chase!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only part of this page that needed fixing was the very last panel.&lt;/strong&gt; I had no problem with how I drew Errie tripping over a tree stump, but the lines in her jeans coincided with the lines in the panel above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the tips I learned from an artist I follow online is that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid what he called &amp;ldquo;tangent lines&amp;rdquo; between panels, so that the lines don&amp;rsquo;t stop a person&amp;rsquo;s eyes from moving around the page.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure enough, the more I looked at this page, the more my eyes stopped at that intersection above this panel. &lt;strong&gt;So I endeavored to modify it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-one-thing-leads-to-another&#34;&gt;But one thing leads to another&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my best to work with the existing linework and save the panel. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But alas!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing I tried sat right with me, so I resorted to redrawing the whole panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid finicking too long on the details, I opted for a silhouette in this panel. Now, after coloring the page, I have no regrets. &lt;strong&gt;It looks awesome!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed tangent lines before, but never with a complete redrawing. &lt;strong&gt;It usually only takes small modification&lt;/strong&gt;, but so much is happening on this page that proved challenging in all my attempts to fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh well&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out all of page 29 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I&amp;rsquo;ll feature one of the first ten pages of Book 1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; And have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;definitely-needed-to-revise-this-page&#34;&gt;Definitely needed to revise this page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was finalizing the character design for Nascha. I felt so certain about the hair style
I gave her. &lt;strong&gt;Now, 2 years later, I look at this page and think that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;
to curb one&amp;rsquo;s style choices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I changed Nascha&amp;rsquo;s hair. I like how her bangs frame her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-important-rule-for-text-in-comics&#34;&gt;An important rule for text in comics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most jarring feature of this page were the walls of text.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel less bad about this cringe-worthy
mistake, since it&amp;rsquo;s apparently a common one made by artists new to drawing comics.
And besides, the stuff that
Nascha says in those walls of text wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to convey any helpful information. It was meant to be
mysterious and not well understood by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That goal didn&amp;rsquo;t change since I drew this page, but after 2
years, I see the disadvantage of having all this text taking up whole panels:
&lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no clear direction to the reader on how to interpret what is going on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is someone talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do I start reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Reads it] &lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;Did I just waste five minutes reading redundant information?!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page makes more sense once Errie starts talking, but I knew it can do better. Therefore, I did away
with the walls of text and created new speech bubbles. &lt;strong&gt;Now, in addition to clarifying what Nascha is saying,
I&amp;rsquo;m introducing a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; mystery in the situation&amp;mdash;the presence of &lt;em&gt;two kinds&lt;/em&gt; of speech bubbles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to the audience to figure out what this means, as the significance will be revealed by the
plot. In fact, you can find some hints in Book 2&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22/&#34;&gt;Check out the rest of page 22!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll post another updated page, one that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; proud of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 14 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 09:09:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;speech-bubbles&#34;&gt;SPEECH BUBBLES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes on this page mostly consist of reformatting the characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue! A &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; changes
were made to what was said, but none were of great consequence. They were a result of trying to
make the conversation and speech bubbles make better sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of, I learned a lot about how to make clearer speech bubbles from a resource that one
of my brothers shared with me. It has a lot of great tips in it about creating dialogue in comics,
many of which about issues I did not foresee. You can find this helpful resource &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blambot.com/articles_tips.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wellllllll&#34;&gt;wellllllll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have much more to say about this page. The only other change on this page (aside from coloring)
was redrawing Chan&amp;rsquo;s hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I decided to work on this before the majority of pages was b/c the dialogue needed to look
right&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;and there is a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of dialogue on this page.&lt;/em&gt; So it got a high rework rating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; updated page has more lineart reworked on it, so the post for it next week will be a
lot more interesting!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14/&#34;&gt;page 14 of Book 1&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to see the next updated page. Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 6 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:46:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;yus&#34;&gt;YUS.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like how this page turned out! I&amp;rsquo;m super proud of the newly-inked Wolf and the colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;color-balance&#34;&gt;Color Balance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the first page I tried out the color balance tool to adjust the colors.&lt;/strong&gt; Basically, I fill
in the areas with the true colors, but then adjust them so that they look more like they would
at a sunrise. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with the results.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go back to page 5 to adjust the colors accordingly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;redrawing-wolf&#34;&gt;Redrawing Wolf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to redo panel 3. I found a good reference to use and redrew Wolf.
&lt;strong&gt;And oh my &lt;em&gt;goodness&lt;/em&gt; this panel is so &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;!!!&lt;/strong&gt; I put a lot of thought into it
and shrunk the guy down so that he&amp;rsquo;s looking &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; at the leaping Wolf. &lt;strong&gt;I always intended
this panel to be comical, but the eye contact between the characters is &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;
Redoing the guy&amp;rsquo;s expression also helped make the panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-glow-around-wolf&#34;&gt;Adding glow around Wolf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original page didn&amp;rsquo;t have any glows around Wolf, but I decided to add it in panel 3 for emphasis.
Therefore, I added the glow around Wolf in the other panels for consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06/&#34;&gt;page 6&lt;/a&gt; of Book 1!
I&amp;rsquo;ll upload another updated page next week, &lt;strong&gt;so have a great weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 28 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:30:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;happy-vines&#34;&gt;Happy Vines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ode to Bob Ross:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reworked page features a variety of happy vines&amp;hellip;a short, stumpy vine here&amp;hellip;a long, slender vine there&amp;hellip;a beautiful scenery&lt;/em&gt; filled &lt;em&gt;with happy vines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s updated page is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28/&#34;&gt;page 28 (Book 1)&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-changed-on-page-28&#34;&gt;What changed on page 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think drawing all the vines in Book 1 had to be the most challenging part of the whole book.&lt;/strong&gt; Part of it
is b/c they&amp;rsquo;re so elaborate and I spend a lot of time on them, &lt;strong&gt;but also the fact that they had to be
&lt;em&gt;glowing&lt;/em&gt; most of the time&lt;/strong&gt; and I &lt;em&gt;draw&lt;/em&gt; all the glows in ink first&amp;hellip;It got a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; over-the-top on some
pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely happy that the reworking of the inks on this page &lt;strong&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t need any changes
on the vines&lt;/strong&gt;. I only modified Errie&amp;rsquo;s surprised expression on panel 2 and &lt;strong&gt;(the most dramatic change)&lt;/strong&gt;
I painstakingly &lt;strong&gt;erased&lt;/strong&gt; all the sound effects that where initially drawn in and recreated them digitally.
&lt;strong&gt;So all those &amp;lsquo;HHH&amp;rsquo;s you see&amp;hellip;they were in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; panel on both page 27 and 28. I erased &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t digging those hand-drawn words and how rough they looked. I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to get rid of them. &lt;strong&gt;So
I did.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore,&lt;/em&gt; in addition to uploading the new images for page 28, &lt;strong&gt;I also uploaded the updated image of page
27&lt;/strong&gt; so that both are consistent on how the sound effects are displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still other pages that have the hard-drawn sound effects, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to update those too when I
get to them. Ironically, I didn&amp;rsquo;t add &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lsquo;HHH&amp;rsquo;s on the following page (29)&amp;hellip;so &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; will be easy to
update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-assessment&#34;&gt;General Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This comic page is one of my more &lt;em&gt;exciting&lt;/em&gt; comic pages (before AND after coloring)&lt;/strong&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s
one of the first action scenes in Book 1 (probably #2, after the settlers&amp;rsquo; flashback). Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t
have to redo much of the inking on it either, I think it was also one of the strongest inked pages I&amp;rsquo;ve
made. The different character positions and angles I chose for all the panels did a good job of portraying
the back-and-forth movement of the character in flight defending herself from the pursuing vines. &lt;strong&gt;I am
especially proud of this action scene b/c it gives a further glimpse into Errie&amp;rsquo;s character&amp;mdash;her quick
response to a threat shows a rare display of resilience and boldness in this soft-spoken teenager.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think one of the reasons it was so well drawn was b/c I actually created a reference to draw
from. &lt;strong&gt;I recorded myself doing the exact swinging motion Errie is doing in the above featured panel&lt;/strong&gt; and
watched the video over and over to get the position just right. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great recording, so no individual
frame seemed suitable for what I wanted, but I got what I needed from the combined series of motions and
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WHA-LA&lt;/em&gt;! I made a panel that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; proud of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on a roll this week coloring more pages! &lt;strong&gt;Next week will feature a page that &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; needed
TLC on the &lt;em&gt;inking&lt;/em&gt; side.&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks again for checking out what&amp;rsquo;s new on &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; and have a great
weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 23 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:58:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23/&#34;&gt;Page 23&lt;/a&gt; of Book 1 is updated!&lt;/strong&gt; The
fourth panel is featured above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to redraw much on this page. &lt;strong&gt;The most change is probably the facial expressions&lt;/strong&gt; in
the second and fourth panels. Just redoing those was a vast improvement for the whole page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also adjusted the drawing of Errie in the second panel. I literally just panned it downwards to make
more space in the panel. It was just&amp;hellip;too &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; to the fourth panel. I was thinking of redrawing it,
but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the drawing was too bad. Sometimes just looking at it and figuring out why it bothers
you helps with solving the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am finding this rework process &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; calming and therapeutic. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to coloring more pages
and sharing another one next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week for another colored page! Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 10 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 12:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome Back!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all had a great holiday season! Thanks to the month off from posting pages,
I got more time and energy to focus on spending time with family and had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that my break is over, I definitely feel more creative energy to work with&amp;hellip;
&lt;em&gt;but not in the way I expected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trial-run&#34;&gt;Trial Run&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was feeling really motivated to color a Book 1 page last week, so I decided to jump on
page 10&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;which is uploaded today, btw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;since
it was &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; finished anyway. I ended up reworking the ink some more on it, but I finished it easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; week I started drawing pages 33 and 34&amp;hellip;and it took all I got just to finish the details
of &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I finished page 33, I sat back to look at both pages, one fully drawn and the other barely started.
I sat like this for probably 10 minutes, just to figure out what I was feeling. I came to the conclusion
that I&amp;rsquo;m still burnt out after my month-long break. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just not motivated to draw new pages right now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, it hit me that I&amp;rsquo;m actually excited about coloring Book 1 pages.&lt;/strong&gt; After drawing page 33, I felt
&lt;em&gt;motivated&lt;/em&gt; to color another Book 1 page and it&amp;rsquo;s nearly done as of writing this post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-reason-for-burnout&#34;&gt;Possible Reason for Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little stunned that I&amp;rsquo;m still not eager to continue Book 2 pages. I decided to look back at my upload
history around this time of the year for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what I found? &lt;strong&gt;I barely took any breaks.&lt;/strong&gt; And when I did, it was out of dire necessity to study
for finals week. That was basically it&amp;hellip; I didn&amp;rsquo;t take an intentional month-long break from updates since
&lt;em&gt;two years&lt;/em&gt; ago. &lt;strong&gt;No wonder I&amp;rsquo;m burnt out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;planning-for-this-year&#34;&gt;Planning for this year&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had in mind a month ago that I should plan on taking time off from drawing this year. &lt;strong&gt;I still think that I
should take a month off in June AND December&lt;/strong&gt;, just to see if it makes a difference in the work I produce.
That means only 10 months to draw, but last year I made only 32 new (fully-colored) pages and 10 reworked/colored
Book 1 pages. That means &lt;strong&gt;I produced 42 pages&lt;/strong&gt;, which is also roughly the &lt;strong&gt;same total number of pages I&amp;rsquo;d produce if I were only working 10 months&lt;/strong&gt; out of the year (10 months * 4 pages a month = 40 pages). &lt;strong&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; counting the miscellaneous posts, like the &amp;lsquo;How I Draw&amp;rsquo; posts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based off of these numbers and the results of my trial run, I think I have nothing to lose by planning for two months of break time this year. &lt;strong&gt;It may even help prevent burnout in years to come&amp;mdash;but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-for-weekly-updates&#34;&gt;As for weekly updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; motivated to keep coloring Book 1 pages, I&amp;rsquo;m going to upload &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; on a weekly basis&lt;/strong&gt;
and create miscellaneous posts to briefly compare/contrast the updated page and share the link to it.
It sucks that I can&amp;rsquo;t give new content right now, but there&amp;rsquo;s no getting around this&amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;page block&amp;rsquo;,
whatever this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep working on pages 33 and 34, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking my sweet time on those. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll
reassess my &amp;lsquo;creative state&amp;rsquo; again in March to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start on weekly page updates
for Book 2. &lt;strong&gt;Worst case scenario, I go through most of this year just coloring Book 1 pages&amp;mdash;really,
that&amp;rsquo;s not so bad.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do those anyway, but I was expecting to do them b/w Book 2 pages.
&lt;em&gt;Mrhh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least I can look forward to this year making Book 1 look like what it does in my head. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actually, I&lt;/em&gt; am
&lt;em&gt;looking forward to it&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-thoughts-until-next-week&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts until next week&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of when I continue Book 2, &lt;strong&gt;I still aim for 40 pages finished by the end of the year.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m
accepting any combination of reworked pages and new pages to reach this goal. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SO HERE GOES!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend and thanks for following! Feel free to like my Facebook page and reread the comic! See
you next week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2018</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 21:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;now-that-i-ve-joked-about-them-i-guess-those-antlers-are-sticking-around&#34;&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve joked about them, I guess those antlers are sticking around&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what can I say?&lt;/strong&gt; They make Christmas posts fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;merry-christmas-and-happy-holidays&#34;&gt;Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my break so far. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to do only one post for the holidays.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stack up too many tasks for myself and be so focused on the amount of workload
ahead of me. &lt;strong&gt;Only needing to finish this one update made drawing it &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you like this goofy Christmas art! I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of the Catz. Especially Catius and his
Chrismas lights&amp;hellip;and Tenti&amp;rsquo;s squid arms&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Well, gosh. I could go on and &lt;em&gt;on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-you-re-probably-wondering-about-the-next-update&#34;&gt;But you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering about the next update!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a deal with myself to &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; draw any pages until January. I want to enjoy this
holiday season &lt;em&gt;as much as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I also want to announce what my upload schedule will be like this coming year and I
still need time to think about it, so &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post a status update January 5th&lt;/strong&gt;. It won&amp;rsquo;t be
a &lt;em&gt;page&lt;/em&gt; update, but &lt;strong&gt;it will contain information on when I will post the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; page update
of the year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I&amp;rsquo;ll have&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;checks calendar&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;three weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to enjoy myself and strategize a little bit on what I&amp;rsquo;ll do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have some writing to do&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;and much staring at page-number stubs pinned to a bulletin board
on my wall and drumming my fingers together in deep concentration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aaaaaaaand I should get back to my break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have a wonderful holiday season! Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check for the next status update on January 5th.
&lt;strong&gt;Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-10-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 11:45:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m extending the delay on page 32. I got as far as adding true colors, but I
still have the text with text bubbles and shading left to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing out about it though, because now&amp;rsquo;s a good time for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;morphic-character-feature&#34;&gt;Morphic Character Feature!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s post features a brief history on &lt;strong&gt;that scary, purple-glowing lady&lt;/strong&gt; in
my timeline of writing &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about keeping her name secret until it was actually mentioned in the
comic, but &lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see any significant repercussions in sharing it, so WHAT THE
HEY.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-tenti-the-squid&#34;&gt;Welcome Tenti the Squid!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with other Morphics, I followed the trend of naming her after the species I
based her off of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;species-and-name-inspiration&#34;&gt;Species and Name Inspiration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much research, I decided to base her off of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giant_squid&#34;&gt;Giant Squid, &lt;em&gt;Architeuthis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
The reason why I went with that specific kind of squid is because that&amp;rsquo;s the
&lt;strong&gt;largest&lt;/strong&gt; of all species of squid and &lt;strong&gt;it may have inspired stories of the
&lt;em&gt;Kraken&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s one of the more &lt;strong&gt;mysterious&lt;/strong&gt; species of squid, such that no one
could verify it&amp;rsquo;s existence except for their dead carcasses washing up on shore.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/edith_widder_how_we_found_the_giant_squid?language=en&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt;
all about some of the first video footage of a live Giant Squid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The species&amp;rsquo; name posed a problem for me in naming Tenti. I was thinking of &amp;lsquo;Toothy&amp;rsquo;
for a while (after &amp;lsquo;Archi&lt;strong&gt;tueth&lt;/strong&gt;is&amp;rsquo;), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to mesh
right with her character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I decided to name her after the number of tentacles a giant squid
has&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. It also meshed well with &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;ten&lt;/strong&gt;tacles&amp;rsquo; and it sounded better than &amp;lsquo;Toothy&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, she&amp;rsquo;s always been very in&lt;strong&gt;ten&lt;/strong&gt;se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could keep going with this train of thought, but you get the idea. &lt;strong&gt;The name clicked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clothing-and-appearance&#34;&gt;Clothing and Appearance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The images above are actual photos of sketches I drew of Tenti, dating from &lt;strong&gt;two years ago&lt;/strong&gt;,
(while writing the first finished script of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;) to &lt;strong&gt;earlier this year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within that timespan, she remained pretty consistent. I held to keeping her
dark-skinned and wearing attire similar to that worn in ancient northern Africa/Egypt.
I was attached to the idea of her wearing a dress at first, but this year &lt;strong&gt;I knew
I wanted to avoid drawing the folds of &lt;em&gt;that skirt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It also made sense to
make her look more like a mummy or dressed like a woman on a wall of an Egyptian
tomb. &lt;strong&gt;Therefore, the &lt;em&gt;really easy&lt;/em&gt; outfit that resulted&lt;/strong&gt; not only satisfied
these criteria, &lt;strong&gt;but also balanced out how hard it is to draw the rest of Tenti&amp;rsquo;s
appearance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, &lt;em&gt;black veins &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; tentacles?! &lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt; she&amp;rsquo;s glowing???&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned into my worst drawing nightmare. I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;glad&lt;/em&gt; her outfit is so darn easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALSO, LAST NOTE ON HER OUTFIT&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m proud that she&amp;rsquo;s still wearing that necklace.
One of the most jarring characteristics of any squid is the &lt;strong&gt;single wide-open
eye&lt;/strong&gt; and the necklace mimics that &lt;strong&gt;perfectly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;powers-and-abilities&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Powers and Abilities&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heheheheheheheheheheheheheheheh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEY&amp;rsquo;RE A SECRET. &lt;em&gt;(For now&amp;hellip;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll just &lt;strong&gt;have to keep reading to find out what her powers are!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But GUESS WHAT&amp;mdash; You won&amp;rsquo;t have to wait long! In fact, &lt;strong&gt;only until the &lt;em&gt;next page&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OOOOOOOoooooOOOOOOOOooooooOOOOOOOOO!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a good feeling that I&amp;rsquo;ll have page 32 up next weekend, but in case I don&amp;rsquo;t,
I&amp;rsquo;ll still upload a fun post!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m giving myself until the end of November to
get this page done, mostly so that I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing myself out over it. However,
I&amp;rsquo;m certain I won&amp;rsquo;t need that deadline, it&amp;rsquo;s just a safety net and I&amp;rsquo;m already
super close to finishing the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;strong&gt;I appreciate your patience&lt;/strong&gt; in my delay to get this page up. As
mentioned above, Tenti is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; easy to draw and I&amp;rsquo;m getting worn out from
drawing/coloring as much as I did this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So check out the next post next weekend, in case I post the page! &lt;strong&gt;Have a great
weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-03-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:14:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ballpoint pen drawings of Errie and Vix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-page-today-hope-you-like-sticky-notes&#34;&gt;No page today&amp;mdash;Hope you like sticky notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time this week to work on page 32. Even before
posting the previous page, I felt more confident about getting it done this
coming week, what with Halloween and All Saint&amp;rsquo;s Day among other things to
worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I still have a lot to get done on page 32 in one week. I still
haven&amp;rsquo;t put text on it, not to mention flatting and coloring. &lt;strong&gt;Therefore,
hopefully it will not surprise anyone if I can&amp;rsquo;t finish page 32 on time again.&lt;/strong&gt;
If that happens, I&amp;rsquo;ll post another no-page update and delay page 32&amp;rsquo;s post
another week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; page I&amp;rsquo;ll finish before I take a break from drawing new pages
for a few months.&lt;/strong&gt; The only reason I&amp;rsquo;m trying so hard to post this page and the last
page despite delays is that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about unfinished pages when I&amp;rsquo;m
on break. I apologize for the late/delayed posts recently. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize until
then that I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; needed a break. This year was the first time I ever colored
pages and it was definitely a learning experience on what I can or cannot handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post for more news about my upcoming break! With a good
schedule this coming week, I should be able to post the next page, &lt;strong&gt;but
we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see!&lt;/strong&gt; If not, I&amp;rsquo;ll still upload some art!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (10-20-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 11:48:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-page-update-today-still-working-on-page-31&#34;&gt;No page update today. Still working on page 31.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough week, but as I mentioned in a previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been
experiencing a bit of drawing fatigue. I think I exhausted my creative energy
and that&amp;rsquo;s not surprising considering that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing AND coloring
&lt;em&gt;30 pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; since March, keeping a &lt;em&gt;weekly&lt;/em&gt; upload schedule, AND on top of that
&lt;em&gt;doing some extra posts&lt;/em&gt; for celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rethink my upload schedule. &lt;strong&gt;I still want to keep
uploading pages until end of November/beginning of December and then take a
month off&lt;/strong&gt;, but I should probably upload less. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking once every two
weeks. It sounds painstakingly slow to follow and I &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; want to have upload
days so infrequently, but I simply can&amp;rsquo;t keep up with a weekly schedule right
now, so that will have to do for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-a-thank-you-for-checking-out-my-comic-here-are-some-sticky-note-drawings&#34;&gt;As a &amp;lsquo;Thank you&amp;rsquo; for checking out my comic, here are some sticky note drawings!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to leave readers hanging, so here are some portraits of the main
characters of &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;! I like to draw in ballpoint pen on sticky notes lately.
It&amp;rsquo;s a very convenient medium. I hope you like them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to have the next page ready next week, so come back then to see it! I&amp;rsquo;ll
have more news about my schedule for uploading pages in that post too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:54:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 4 of my drawing process!
We are now at the final post dedicated to showing how I
create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out
page 27! Just click the link to go back a page to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-4-color-stage&#34;&gt;Part 4: Color Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I talked about using GIMP to turn my pages from
image files to layered lines and text. This week I’m talking
about my coloring process and creating the final image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-open-file-and-apply-settings&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open file and apply settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set the image mode from ‘Greyscale’ to ‘RGB’. An image
set to the former will not show color, even when you paint
with a selected color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-flatting&#34;&gt;Step 2: Flatting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where my process seems a little counter-intuitive.
I color the areas of the page with &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; colors before
filling them in with their true colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easier to go back and change the color of something,
like Vix’s coat. If I realize I used the wrong shade of red,
I can select Vix’s coat in all panels of the page by using
the ‘Select By Color’ tool and fill in all areas with the
correct color.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: While it is true I could select by color with the
true colors, if something other than Vix’s coat is the
same red, those areas will be selected too. Selection is
simpler when these areas are distinguished and this
distinguishment is possible by flatting these areas in
different colors on a different layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hear that flatting leads to more efficient coloring time.
Basically I’m filling in the areas to select before even
deciding what color these areas are going to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the flatting process. It’s like coloring a
coloring book without caring about the color combination.
It’s very refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;I create a layer underneath the lines layer and fill
in areas one color at a time, unselecting those areas by
color so that I don’t paint over them accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-3-add-true-colors&#34;&gt;Part 3: Add True Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the easy part of the coloring process. Now that I
have my flats layer, I only have to Select By Color on that
layer and fill in all those areas on another layer (under
the lines layer) with the true color. I don’t like creating
a lot of unnecessary layers, so I would typically create
two, one for foreground and one for background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use the same colors I used before on previous
pages, I open up the necessary files and use the ‘Color
Picker’ tool to select the true color and fill in the areas
on the current file with that color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I add whatever colors I want. I often use
gradients (color blends) for the backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-4-shading-brights&#34;&gt;Part 4: Shading/Brights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LAST STEP!&lt;/strong&gt; This step is a little longer than it looks…
First I create two layers, one for shading and one for
highlights. Then I add a layer mask to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what’s a layer mask?&lt;/strong&gt; It’s like another layer, but it
controls the transparency of the visible layer it’s
attached to. I use it mostly to add gradient effects in
the shading/brights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently use a shade of blue-green for shading and pure
white for highlights. I paint with these colors directly
on the layers and adjust their transparency on the layer’s
corresponding mask to make them semi-transparent so that
the true colors below them to show up a little, giving
the illusion of depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-just-kidding-this-is-really-the-last-step&#34;&gt;Step 5: Just kidding, this is really the last step…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah! We need to export this thing. Right now the file
is still not an image file you can upload to the internet.
It is still a .xcf file, which is only displayable in GIMP.
I have to export it to .jpg format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ‘File-&amp;gt;Export as…’, use default settings, and &lt;em&gt;WHA-LA!&lt;/em&gt;
The image appears in the specified folder!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;And all these substeps take me about 2 hours on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this little run-through of how I make
pages. Feel free to try out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;!
It’s helpful for me and
I recommend it for basic image-layer editing. You could
draw from scratch on it if you wanted to. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it,
but I personally find that I draw way better traditionally
than by computer, so I only use it for simple things like
outlines, speech bubbles, text, and select-and-fill style
coloring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other possible software you could use for digital drawing
include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adobe Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clip Studio/Manga Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, I’ll get off my soapbox now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HAPPY BIRTHDAY MORPHIC!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m done celebrating now. Thanks again for reading and
have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 3 of my drawing process!
We are now at the third of four posts dedicated to showing
how I create the pages of “Morphic”. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to check
out page 26!&lt;/strong&gt; Just click the left arrow icon to go back a
page and see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-text-stage&#34;&gt;Part 3: Text Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the drawing process starts to get techy. I use
a program called GIMP for adding text and color layers to
my pages. It’s like Photoshop except it’s open source and
managed by a community of developers. You can download it
free of charge &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-open-the-file&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open the file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin by starting GIMP and opening my scanned image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-create-layers&#34;&gt;Step 2: Create Layers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My image is automatically opens as its own layer. I add two
more layers&amp;ndash;one filled with white and one that stays
transparent. I put the white layer below all other layers
and the transparent one on top, sandwiching the scanned
image in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-single-out-lines&#34;&gt;Step 3: Single out lines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my goal&amp;ndash;I want to keep the lines visible, but be
able to see through the white spaces between them. There
are different ways of accomplishing this, but basically
what I do is select the whole area that’s black on the
image layer (only lines are selected, no white-space),
select the transparent layer, and fill the selection with
black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I hide the image layer, but the lines are still there.
If I hide the top/transparent layer, the lines disappear
and only white shows up. If I show that layer again and
hide the white layer, only the lines show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-crop-images&#34;&gt;Step 4: Crop Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create two new files that are copies of the original
layers file. Then I use a cropping tool to cut out the
parts I want&amp;mdash;the first page on the first file and the
second page on the second file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-add-text&#34;&gt;Step 5: Add Text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On each image file, I add editable text layers using the
‘Text’ tool and move them around. The typefaces I use are a
mix of my own custom-made fonts (using a free
typeface-generation website) and open-source fonts
available from Google. I mostly use one I had generated
based on my own handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-6-draw-speech-bubbles&#34;&gt;Step 6: Draw Speech Bubbles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a variety of selection tools and path tools to shape
the areas that become speech bubbles. After filling the
areas with white, I stroke with the paintbrush tool.
Sometimes I even do more than one bubbles layer, to get a
layering effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;edit-undo-is-my-friend&#34;&gt;‘Edit-&amp;gt;Undo’ is my friend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes order matters in the way I create speech bubbles
or anything else, so I frequently test changes and undo
those I don’t like. &lt;em&gt;Who doesn’t…?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three stages down, one to go! Check out next week’s posts
for the regular page update AND the post for Stage 4, the
COLORING STAGE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:24:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 2 of my drawing process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now at the second of four posts dedicated to
showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. But don’t
worry&amp;ndash;page 25 is also posted! Just click the left
navigation button to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-ink-stage&#34;&gt;Part 2: Ink Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all four stages, this one is definitely the
shortest. It often takes me under an hour to ink one page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-prep&#34;&gt;Step 1: Prep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin by taping the pencil drawing onto a flat surface,
which is usually a table or clipboard. Then I tape a sheet
of tracing paper over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-inking&#34;&gt;Step 2: Inking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I draw with several sizes of black ink pen, but I typically
use size 005 for the main content of each page. The tracing
paper is thin enough for me to see the pencil lines through
it as I draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also gotten into the practice of drawing with my hand
on another sheet of paper on top of the tracing paper,
shifting it around as I draw. This is so that I don’t get
oil from my hands on the tracing paper because I noticed
early on that my inked lines didn’t look so great and they
looked far better when I started drawing with minimal skin
contact on the tracing paper. I’m guessing that the oil on
my hands was repelling the ink as it was drying and it
affected the quality of the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-scanning&#34;&gt;Step 3: Scanning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the drawing, I untape both the ink drawing
and the pencil drawing. I place the ink drawing in the
scanner and align the edges. Then I run the scanner with black and white
settings so that the image only contains straight black and
white pixels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have an image saved on my laptop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out next week’s posts for the regular page update AND the post for Stage 3, the text stage!
Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>