<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2019</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2019/</guid>
      <description>I hope you had a Happy Thanksgiving!
It&amp;rsquo;s the moment you have been waiting for&amp;hellip;
Christmas Doodle! &amp;hellip;Heheh.
Ok, moving on to what you were really waiting for&amp;hellip;
I finalized 17 pages! They&amp;rsquo;re all in different sections of Book 1, so here are the links to each individual page that&amp;rsquo;s updated as of this post. Check &amp;lsquo;em out!
 Page 18
 Page 19
 Page 20
 Page 21</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update!</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/status-update-07-06-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 13:08:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/status-update-07-06-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! I hope you had a happy 4th of July!
As promised prior to my month-long break, I shall update you on how things are going from my end.
Where I&amp;rsquo;m at now This week, I finished the pencil stage for pages 35, 36, and 37 and started the pencil stage for page 38. I have also finished flatting 4 pages from Book 1.
As you can probably guess, I won&amp;rsquo;t have a page ready for posting next week&amp;mdash;or for the rest of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 42 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:04:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s all the reworked pages&amp;hellip;for now! Thanks for your patience as I took time to figure out my writer&amp;rsquo;s/artist&amp;rsquo;s block. It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird experience for me to keep updating on a weekly basis without adding to the story line.
I hope you enjoyed reading my posts regarding changes to pages in Book 1! I reworked all the pages that required the most notable changes aside from coloring, so from here on out it should just be coloring that&amp;rsquo;s left to do on the rest of Book 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 41 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 14:17:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</guid>
      <description>A Necessary Change Maybe I mentioned this before, but when I drew Capri as a goat for the first time in the story I drew him with a necklace, but then afterwards changed my mind. I was originally going to draw all morphics with their unique stones on necklaces, which they would wear around their neck.
Although the rationale isn&amp;rsquo;t revealed yet for why morphics have these stones on their chest, I&amp;rsquo;m ok with sharing the reason for the design change, since it isn&amp;rsquo;t really significant to the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 61 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 09:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</guid>
      <description>This was a fun page! I enjoyed painting the galaxy background in the reworked panel. It was also fun to redraw the portrayal of the characters in the same panel&amp;mdash;The original silhouettes didn&amp;rsquo;t appear clear enough.
I made some progress on Book 2 pages Pages 33 and 34 are still underway, but I finished inking one and now I&amp;rsquo;m halfway inking the other.
My plan is to get these two pages done and upload them the two final weeks before I take my month-long break in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 47 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:52:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</guid>
      <description>Another cool page! Not much rework here, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to clean it up a bit!
&amp;hellip;
Well, not much else to say this week. But I finished another reworked page! So now I just need to finish content for two more updates.
Thanks for reading! Check out the complete page 47. Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll upload another reworked page that looks cool!
Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 60 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 11:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</guid>
      <description>WOOOOOOOOOO I&amp;rsquo;m happy to finally experiment with coloring the inside of a blue door!
I might come back to this page when I figure out a style I like, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have some portrayal of what it looks like when someone goes into a blue door.
Still Writing Book 2&amp;rsquo;s plotline I think I&amp;rsquo;m making great progress! I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to figure out how a lot of the plot points lead into each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 38 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 12:07:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</guid>
      <description>I Guess I Can Draw Goats Now I am so happy that I fixed Capri&amp;rsquo;s goat face in this page. I didn&amp;rsquo;t use any references to draw him! As a result, he looked less like a goat and more like a&amp;hellip;dog?
[Realizes an eerie resemblance to a former family pet.]
Well anyway&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a short update from behind-the-scenes. It had been many weeks since making any serious progress on Book 1 pages, but this week I finished one page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 36 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 18:24:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</guid>
      <description>A Fun Experiment I am glad to be coloring Book 1 pages for many reasons. One of those reasons consists of an excuse to practice shading and lighting.
I&amp;rsquo;ve colored enough pages of Book 1 to figure out that my style needs to change in regards to lighting and shading. I started experimenting in some of these pages I uploaded recently, including this one. Here I stuck to using one color each for shading and light (and almost the same transparency across each layer), but allowing myself to &amp;lsquo;smudge&amp;rsquo; or blend the colors on each layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 35 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 18:31:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this page. Awesome colors! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with how well the backgrounds in the different panels complement each other.
Like a lot of pages in this scene, the rework on the inks involved fixing how I drew Capri. Although I deliberately made him a dislikable character, it&amp;rsquo;s bad when multiple panels of the character makes me grimace. I think I should have practiced drawing him a lot more before he appeared in the comic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 33 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 14:31:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</guid>
      <description>Another week, another reworked page! Only one thing to say about this page&amp;mdash;Capri looks a lot more surprised without his mouth gaping open!
No other news except that I&amp;rsquo;m still making progress on sketching the plot of Book 2. I think it&amp;rsquo;s coming along pretty well, and I&amp;rsquo;m slowly growing more confident in the story line.
I did slow my pace on Book 1 production so that I can focus on other things, so next week&amp;rsquo;s page will be another reworked page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 32 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</guid>
      <description>Not a very interesting reworked page today, so how about some discussion?
You&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering how I&amp;rsquo;m choosing the order of pages to color, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that.
Gameplan: The First Sweep Perhaps I mentioned before, but I&amp;rsquo;m first hitting all the pages that clearly need ink rework. Since a high concentration of these pages are in the first half of the book, this means that the first half will look more &amp;lsquo;done&amp;rsquo; than the second half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 30 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 18:10:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</guid>
      <description>Splash! This page was a doozy! I spent a long time just on the water.
I&amp;rsquo;m still not thrilled with how the splash looks, but it looks better than it did. I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it and if it still bothers me in a year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep working on it. For now, IT&amp;rsquo;S FINE.
&amp;hellip;Same goes for a lot of these pages.
Rework Plan continued Quick update on where I&amp;rsquo;m at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colored Pages 2, 3, 4, and 8 (Book 1)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:25:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</guid>
      <description>Settlers-scene all done!
I decided to get all the pages in this scene out of the way. This scene only ranges from 2 through 8 (seven pages). I feel less cringy about these &amp;ldquo;flashback&amp;rdquo; pages now that they&amp;rsquo;re colored and the text boxes look cleaner.
The featured images above are the parts of the pages I like the most, but I sense, as I look back over the pages, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming back to touch up the coloring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 7 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</guid>
      <description>Wolf! I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with this redone page! I was originally just going to fill in the existing line work digitally, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too sure with the result, so I redrew Wolf. It looks SO much better!
The following changes were made to page 7:  Redrew panel 1 (kept the same glow lines). Colored whole page. Redrew text boxes and updated text box fonts. Updated sound effect in panel 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</guid>
      <description>Back to the chase! The only part of this page that needed fixing was the very last panel. I had no problem with how I drew Errie tripping over a tree stump, but the lines in her jeans coincided with the lines in the panel above.
One of the tips I learned from an artist I follow online is that it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid what he called &amp;ldquo;tangent lines&amp;rdquo; between panels, so that the lines don&amp;rsquo;t stop a person&amp;rsquo;s eyes from moving around the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</guid>
      <description>Definitely needed to revise this page I remember when I was finalizing the character design for Nascha. I felt so certain about the hair style I gave her. Now, 2 years later, I look at this page and think that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like time to curb one&amp;rsquo;s style choices.
So I changed Nascha&amp;rsquo;s hair. I like how her bangs frame her face.
An important rule for text in comics The most jarring feature of this page were the walls of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 14 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 09:09:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</guid>
      <description>SPEECH BUBBLES Changes on this page mostly consist of reformatting the characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue! A few changes were made to what was said, but none were of great consequence. They were a result of trying to make the conversation and speech bubbles make better sense.
Speaking of, I learned a lot about how to make clearer speech bubbles from a resource that one of my brothers shared with me. It has a lot of great tips in it about creating dialogue in comics, many of which about issues I did not foresee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 6 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:46:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</guid>
      <description>YUS. I really like how this page turned out! I&amp;rsquo;m super proud of the newly-inked Wolf and the colors.
Color Balance This is the first page I tried out the color balance tool to adjust the colors. Basically, I fill in the areas with the true colors, but then adjust them so that they look more like they would at a sunrise. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with the results.
Now I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go back to page 5 to adjust the colors accordingly&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 28 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:30:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</guid>
      <description>Happy Vines Ode to Bob Ross:
This week&amp;rsquo;s reworked page features a variety of happy vines&amp;hellip;a short, stumpy vine here&amp;hellip;a long, slender vine there&amp;hellip;a beautiful scenery filled with happy vines.
This week&amp;rsquo;s updated page is page 28 (Book 1)!
What changed on page 28 I think drawing all the vines in Book 1 had to be the most challenging part of the whole book. Part of it is b/c they&amp;rsquo;re so elaborate and I spend a lot of time on them, but also the fact that they had to be glowing most of the time and I draw all the glows in ink first&amp;hellip;It got a little over-the-top on some pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 23 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:58:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! Page 23 of Book 1 is updated! The fourth panel is featured above.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to redraw much on this page. The most change is probably the facial expressions in the second and fourth panels. Just redoing those was a vast improvement for the whole page.
I also adjusted the drawing of Errie in the second panel. I literally just panned it downwards to make more space in the panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 10 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 12:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome Back! I hope you all had a great holiday season! Thanks to the month off from posting pages, I got more time and energy to focus on spending time with family and had a great time.
Now that my break is over, I definitely feel more creative energy to work with&amp;hellip; but not in the way I expected.
Trial Run I was feeling really motivated to color a Book 1 page last week, so I decided to jump on page 10&amp;ndash;which is uploaded today, btw&amp;ndash;since it was mostly finished anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2018</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 21:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve joked about them, I guess those antlers are sticking around&amp;hellip; But what can I say? They make Christmas posts fun!
Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays! I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my break so far. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to do only one post for the holidays. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stack up too many tasks for myself and be so focused on the amount of workload ahead of me. Only needing to finish this one update made drawing it very fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-10-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 11:45:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m extending the delay on page 32. I got as far as adding true colors, but I still have the text with text bubbles and shading left to do.
I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing out about it though, because now&amp;rsquo;s a good time for&amp;hellip;
Morphic Character Feature! Today&amp;rsquo;s post features a brief history on that scary, purple-glowing lady in my timeline of writing &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;!
I thought about keeping her name secret until it was actually mentioned in the comic, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see any significant repercussions in sharing it, so WHAT THE HEY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-03-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:14:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</guid>
      <description>Ballpoint pen drawings of Errie and Vix
No page today&amp;mdash;Hope you like sticky notes As expected, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time this week to work on page 32. Even before posting the previous page, I felt more confident about getting it done this coming week, what with Halloween and All Saint&amp;rsquo;s Day among other things to worry about.
Nevertheless, I still have a lot to get done on page 32 in one week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (10-20-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 11:48:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</guid>
      <description>No page update today. Still working on page 31. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough week, but as I mentioned in a previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing a bit of drawing fatigue. I think I exhausted my creative energy and that&amp;rsquo;s not surprising considering that I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing AND coloring 30 pages since March, keeping a weekly upload schedule, AND on top of that doing some extra posts for celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:54:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 4 of my drawing process! We are now at the final post dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out page 27! Just click the link to go back a page to see it.
Part 4: Color Stage Last week, I talked about using GIMP to turn my pages from image files to layered lines and text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 3 of my drawing process! We are now at the third of four posts dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out page 26! Just click the left arrow icon to go back a page and see it.
Part 3: Text Stage Here’s where the drawing process starts to get techy. I use a program called GIMP for adding text and color layers to my pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:24:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 2 of my drawing process!
We are now at the second of four posts dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. But don’t worry&amp;ndash;page 25 is also posted! Just click the left navigation button to see it.
Part 2: Ink Stage Out of all four stages, this one is definitely the shortest. It often takes me under an hour to ink one page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Have you ever wondered how digital art is made? Many styles exist, as do many methods. To celebrate two years of drawing “Morphic”, I’m happy to share a glimpse into my drawing process. I have a lot to say about each stage, so I’ll be dedicating four separate posts to cover how I make a page, one post for each stage. Regular page updates are still going and you can check them out by pressing the back/forward icons or clicking a recent post link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #5</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 23:40:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_5/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s one wishlist item checked off my list: Lane jamming out to tunes on her headphones.
Good news! I started drawing pages for Book 2.
I would have liked to finish writing Book 3 before drawing, but I decided to take the plunge and come back to it. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about graphic novels is that I can go back and forth between writing and drawing when I need to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 20:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Wolf Will you look at that&amp;mdash;It&amp;rsquo;s COLOR!
Usually I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have time to complete the coloring for a picture, but I got this portrait done in less than two days, including the coloring. This fact alone suggests two things:
 I&amp;rsquo;m finally figuring out how I like my coloring, and I have the ability to color in a short amount of time after all.  However, this portrait is a very simple one with a minimal color palette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/capri-art-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 07:42:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/capri-art-update/</guid>
      <description>The main antagonist of Book 1. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to drawing a portrait of Capri and his vines for some time.
Extending Break By Two Weeks I&amp;rsquo;m still in the process of rewriting the series. I got really busy the past couple of weeks and I had enough time for intermission art and launching a website (and cleaning up the bugs following launch).
Not to worry though! That&amp;rsquo;s an excuse enough for me to draw more character portraits anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 19:07:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_2/</guid>
      <description>New Site Launched! I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of myself for getting this site done!
 I uploaded all the pages for Book 1, plus the latest art updates. You can navigate to any part of the plot easily!  &amp;lsquo;Recent Posts&amp;rsquo; on the side bar shows latest content. &amp;lsquo;Blog&amp;rsquo; on the navigation menu displays posts from earliest to latest. Plus I included navigation to previous/next posts at the top and bottom of each post!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/errie-art-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:05:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/errie-art-update/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2017</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 17:30:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2016</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>