<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:04:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 42 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:04:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;that-s-all-the-reworked-pages-for-now&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all the reworked pages&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;for now!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your patience as I took time to figure out my writer&amp;rsquo;s/artist&amp;rsquo;s block.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird experience for me to keep updating on a weekly basis without adding to the story line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hope you enjoyed reading my posts regarding changes to pages in Book 1!&lt;/strong&gt;
I reworked all the pages that required the most notable changes aside from coloring, so from here on out it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; just be coloring that&amp;rsquo;s left to do on the rest of Book 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be making weekly posts about them anymore.
I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the text content for them would sound &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-on-pages-33-and-34-of-book-2&#34;&gt;Status on pages 33 and 34 of Book 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in the middle of coloring both pages.
&lt;strong&gt;I anticipate having page 33 done in time to upload it as next week&amp;rsquo;s post!&lt;/strong&gt;
I should only need to add lighting and shading to finish it.
&lt;strong&gt;Then I will finish coloring page 34 and post that the following week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;year-to-date-progress&#34;&gt;Year to date progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, page 42 of Book 1 marks the 20th page I got done this year!
&lt;strong&gt;I am almost half way to my goal of making/finishing 42(ish) pages by December.&lt;/strong&gt;
(42 is how many pages I produced and uploaded last year.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heheh&amp;hellip;I mentioned &amp;lsquo;42&amp;rsquo; in every sentence of that paragraph.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42/&#34;&gt;page 42&lt;/a&gt; in full color!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll break the cycle and post the long-awaited page 33 of Book 2!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 41 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 14:17:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-necessary-change&#34;&gt;A Necessary Change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I mentioned this before, but when I drew Capri as a goat for the first time in the story I drew him with a necklace, but then afterwards changed my mind.
&lt;strong&gt;I was originally going to draw &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; morphics with their unique stones on necklaces, which they would wear around their neck.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the rationale isn&amp;rsquo;t revealed yet for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; morphics have these stones on their chest, I&amp;rsquo;m ok with sharing the reason for the design change, since it isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; significant to the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to suggest the &lt;em&gt;permanence&lt;/em&gt; of these stones&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;that is, they can&amp;rsquo;t be easily taken from their bearers.&lt;/strong&gt;
Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty silly to continue drawing these stones as necklaces, which imply the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the change. And it was an easy one too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lighting-and-shading&#34;&gt;Lighting and Shading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I mentioned in the last post that the lighting and shading on this page is the look I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to pursue on all my pages.
&lt;em&gt;Maybe&lt;/em&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t tell, but &lt;strong&gt;notice the sharpness of the lights and darks&lt;/strong&gt;.
I want to keep that sharpness as much as possible, instead of blurring &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; those edges across the page.
It conveys more confidence in my lighting/shading &lt;strong&gt;and it looks cool!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still learning how to improve my lighting/shading technique as I go along, so I might go back and touch up this page a bit. &lt;strong&gt;However, I like the overall look to it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progress-on-pages-33-and-34-of-book-2&#34;&gt;Progress on pages 33 and 34 of Book 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished inking this week!
And I began flatting them&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;I am on track for uploading the finished page 33 in 2 weeks and page 34 the week after that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; start to the year, having these two pages started but not finished for so long.
&lt;strong&gt;I am excited not only to get them done (finally), but also to share how they&amp;rsquo;re turning out!&lt;/strong&gt;
I think the hard work I put into them really shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out the fully-colored &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41/&#34;&gt;page 41&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I&amp;rsquo;ll post the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; reworked page I have in my buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right&amp;mdash;We&amp;rsquo;re almost there, folks!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 pages&lt;/strong&gt; in Book 1 redone and uploaded this year! &lt;em&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t that crazy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about it next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 61 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 09:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;this-was-a-fun-page&#34;&gt;This was a fun page!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I enjoyed painting the galaxy background in the reworked panel.&lt;/strong&gt;
It was also fun to redraw the portrayal of the characters in the same panel&amp;mdash;The original silhouettes didn&amp;rsquo;t appear clear enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-made-some-progress-on-book-2-pages&#34;&gt;I made some progress on Book 2 pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages 33 and 34 are &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; underway, but &lt;strong&gt;I finished inking one and now I&amp;rsquo;m halfway inking the other.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to get these two pages done and upload them the two final weeks before I take my month-long break in June.
&lt;strong&gt;I think I can do it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the fullly-colored &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61/&#34;&gt;page 61&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to come back next week&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;the next reworked page I&amp;rsquo;ll share has the lighting/shading style I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about using on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the pages!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 47 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:52:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;another-cool-page&#34;&gt;Another cool page!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much rework here, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to clean it up a bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, not much else to say this week. &lt;strong&gt;But I finished another reworked page!&lt;/strong&gt; So now I just need to finish content for two more updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the complete &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47/&#34;&gt;page 47&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll upload another reworked page that &lt;em&gt;looks cool!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 60 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 11:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;woooooooooo&#34;&gt;WOOOOOOOOOO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to finally experiment with coloring the inside of a blue door!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might come back to this page when I figure out a style I like, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have some portrayal of what it looks like when someone goes into a blue door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;still-writing-book-2-s-plotline&#34;&gt;Still Writing Book 2&amp;rsquo;s plotline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m making great progress!&lt;/strong&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to figure out how a lot of the plot points lead into each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I drew enough panels at this point such that Book 2 will turn out to be longer than Book 1.
&lt;strong&gt;BUT OH WELL.&lt;/strong&gt;
I think it will be &lt;em&gt;worth it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;making-some-progress-on-pages-33-and-34-of-book-2&#34;&gt;Making some progress on pages 33 and 34 of Book 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to give in and just experiment working on these pages via GIMP.
&lt;strong&gt;I figured out last week how to draw lines with changing size as I&amp;rsquo;m drawing on my Wacom tablet!&lt;/strong&gt;
This breakthrough opens up the possibility of inking my pages digitally, &lt;em&gt;so why &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; try it out?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have an easier time figuring out the layout of page 34 if I do it digitally.
&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;page 34&lt;/em&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s been giving me the hardest time to go forward with Book 2!&lt;/strong&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s like the first page of a scene that I hardly gave much thought to&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;visually&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;and that scene is necessary to the plot, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much &lt;em&gt;action&lt;/em&gt; in it that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mess it up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, &lt;strong&gt;as much as I like drawing traditionally and keeping my skills sharp,&lt;/strong&gt; I see a need to evolve my drawing process at this point.
&lt;strong&gt;I actually feel pretty excited about doing more drawing digitally!&lt;/strong&gt;
I might flip back and forth between traditional and digital for the lineart, but I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to keep the style consistent, at least throughout Book 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out the fully-colored &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60/&#34;&gt;page 60&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;
Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll post another reworked page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a happy Easter and a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 38 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 12:07:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-guess-i-can-draw-goats-now&#34;&gt;I Guess I Can Draw Goats Now&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; happy that I fixed Capri&amp;rsquo;s goat face in this page.&lt;/strong&gt;
I didn&amp;rsquo;t use &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; references to draw him!
&lt;strong&gt;As a result, he looked less like a goat and more like a&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;dog&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Realizes an eerie resemblance to a former family pet.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;well-anyway&#34;&gt;Well anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a short update from behind-the-scenes.&lt;/strong&gt;
It had been many weeks since making any serious progress on Book 1 pages, &lt;strong&gt;but &lt;em&gt;this week&lt;/em&gt; I finished &lt;em&gt;one page!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now there&amp;rsquo;s one new page in my buffer and I need content for &lt;em&gt;two more posts&lt;/em&gt; before my established June break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I seem to have lost interest in coloring Book 1 pages now, I&amp;rsquo;m considering other possible content to post for those last two weeks of activity.
&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure about having any Book 2 pages done before then, so those posts might contain new artwork instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I favor the latter a lot more right now, b/c it would be a fresh outlet for creativity &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it might help me regain enthusiasm to continue either Book 1 coloring or new pages in Book 2 after my break.
&lt;strong&gt;In addition, creating new art will give me the opportunity to try out some new drawing or coloring techniques, which is always fun to try!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38/&#34;&gt;page 38&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;
Check it out in full color!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post another reworked page next week! &lt;strong&gt;It has some &lt;em&gt;cool effects!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 36 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 18:24:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fun-experiment&#34;&gt;A Fun Experiment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am glad to be coloring Book 1 pages for many reasons.&lt;/strong&gt; One of those reasons consists of an excuse to practice shading and lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve colored enough pages of Book 1 to figure out that my style needs to change in regards to lighting and shading. I started experimenting in some of these pages I uploaded recently, including this one. &lt;strong&gt;Here I stuck to using one color each for shading and light (and almost the same transparency across each layer), but allowing myself to &amp;lsquo;smudge&amp;rsquo; or blend the colors on each layer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-blending&#34;&gt;No blending?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In contrast to the hard-edged shading/lighting I typically use, the shading/light on this page looks &lt;em&gt;closer&lt;/em&gt; to what I want my pages to look.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt;, I heard a tip from another artist sometime after coloring this page, saying that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell beginning artists from professionals because the former do a lot more unnecessary blending in their coloring.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s generally &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; to stick to hard-edged coloring with as little blending as possible. Too &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; blending and it looks overdone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I figured out a compromise. I&amp;rsquo;ll still color without blending, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll start experimenting with layer modes, different colors, and multiple areas of different transparencies on the shading/lighting layers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will add more flexibility to distinguishing the state of different objects. For instance, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to shade Errie and Lane in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s more obvious when their clothes are wet.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s always bugged me that, after the page in which they stepped out of the pond, it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious that they were &lt;em&gt;soaked&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Lighting and shading will certainly remedy that problem, which makes it super important that I get the technique right!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36/&#34;&gt;page 36&lt;/a&gt; in full color!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate you following my journey as I figure out the best way to proceed with my graphic novel series. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much progress to report right now, either in Book 1 or 2, &lt;strong&gt;but I still have a buffer of a few pages left!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;ll post another reworked page next week! I&amp;rsquo;ll give more details on what&amp;rsquo;s going on behind the scenes in that post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 35 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 18:31:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-m-satisfied-with-this-page&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this page.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome colors! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with how well the backgrounds in the different panels complement each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of pages in this scene, the rework on the inks involved fixing how I drew Capri. &lt;strong&gt;Although I deliberately made him a dislikable character, it&amp;rsquo;s bad when multiple panels of the character makes me grimace.&lt;/strong&gt; I think I should have practiced drawing him a lot more before he appeared in the comic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortunately, I only had to fix one panel on this page!&lt;/strong&gt; (Capri&amp;rsquo;s curls looked a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; too perfect to take him seriously&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the fully-colored &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35/&#34;&gt;page 35&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll share another reworked page, as usual! &lt;strong&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 33 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 14:31:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;another-week-another-reworked-page&#34;&gt;Another week, another reworked page!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one thing to say about this page&amp;mdash;Capri looks &lt;strong&gt;a lot more surprised&lt;/strong&gt; without his mouth gaping open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other news except that I&amp;rsquo;m still making progress on sketching the plot of Book 2. I think it&amp;rsquo;s coming along pretty well, and I&amp;rsquo;m slowly growing more confident in the story line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did slow my pace on Book 1 production so that I can focus on other things, &lt;strong&gt;so next week&amp;rsquo;s page will be another reworked page!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the reworked page!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 32 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Not a very interesting reworked page today, &lt;strong&gt;so how about some discussion?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering &lt;strong&gt;how I&amp;rsquo;m choosing the order of pages to color&lt;/strong&gt;, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gameplan-the-first-sweep&#34;&gt;Gameplan: The First Sweep&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I mentioned before, but &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m first hitting all the pages that clearly need ink rework.&lt;/strong&gt; Since a high concentration of these pages are in the first half of the book, this means that the first half will look more &amp;lsquo;done&amp;rsquo; than the second half. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure that will look confusing, but oh well&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip;this also means that, &lt;strong&gt;(1) as I get better at coloring with every page, I&amp;rsquo;ll look back at the pages I colored and want to change them.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m already seeing it now, as I&amp;rsquo;m figuring out a better way of applying lighting and shading that builds off of the techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve been using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition &lt;strong&gt;(2) I may discover an inconsistency b/w consecutive pages.&lt;/strong&gt; If I color a page, move on to other pages, and then come back to the one directly before or after it, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that I&amp;rsquo;ll notice a difference that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be there. For instance, I noticed that a page I was coloring had glowing in it, but the previous page (which I colored earlier) did not when it logically should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these first colored pages will be &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; on inking, but still need fixes on coloring &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; any perceived inconsistencies. &lt;strong&gt;I call this the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;first sweep&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the first sweep is to make all pages of Book 1 look good on the ink level and at the same time lay down the groundwork for coloring. &lt;strong&gt;This sweep only focuses on the pages that need the most work, but I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with these pages and I&amp;rsquo;m already starting on pages belonging to the &lt;em&gt;second sweep&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gameplan-the-second-sweep&#34;&gt;Gameplan: The Second Sweep&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the first, the main goals of the second sweep are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color all pages with finalized style of base colors, lighting, and shading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain consistent shading, lighting, and base colors for pages with same characters in same settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final check on good inking and text bubbles (including font changes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since consistency if super important in finalizing the pages, &lt;strong&gt;the best stategy to avoid overlooking inconsistencies is to work on these pages in batches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I want to focus on getting most of the uncolored pages done first, while still reworking existing colors as I go along. &lt;strong&gt;Therefore, since the second half of the book is mostly uncolored, I&amp;rsquo;m going to work on pages in sections starting from the end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;pages are categorized into &amp;ldquo;sections&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;batches&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; based on compared scenery, &lt;strong&gt;so that I can use the same or similar lighting and shading across all the pages in a given batch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll post another reworked page, &lt;strong&gt;but don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32/&#34;&gt;page 32&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 30 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 18:10:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;splash&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splash!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was a &lt;strong&gt;doozy!&lt;/strong&gt; I spent a long time just on the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not thrilled with how the splash looks, but it looks better than it did. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it and if it still bothers me in a year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep working on it. For now, IT&amp;rsquo;S FINE.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Same goes for a lot of these pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rework-plan-continued&#34;&gt;Rework Plan continued&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick update on where I&amp;rsquo;m at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; pages reworked and colored (not all uploaded)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; pages left to color (two of them call for rework)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So out of 74 pages in Book 1, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;43%&lt;/strong&gt; of the way done&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;almost half-way!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that most of the finished pages needed the most work, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimistic about getting the rest of the pages done in less time&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; but I still hold reservations about whether I&amp;rsquo;ll stay motivated to keep going with Book 1 pages before transitioning back into Book 2. Of course, the only way I&amp;rsquo;ll know is by trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-term goal: get enough pages done for &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; more weekly updates!&lt;/strong&gt; I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how many pages I have ready to upload, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough to cover all but 3 weeks before June (my break month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I say 3 weekly updates, I don&amp;rsquo;t just mean single page updates&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;some weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll upload &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; pages!&lt;/strong&gt; Like &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only doing that b/c I&amp;rsquo;m so far ahead on these reworked pages.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to feature a before-and-after comparison of color-only pages, as the changes won&amp;rsquo;t be as drastic. In addition, these color-only pages should proceed fast enough to upload them in batches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I&amp;rsquo;ll take my month-long break and I&amp;rsquo;ll decide how to proceed with my update schedule when I return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30/&#34;&gt;page 30&lt;/a&gt;, fully-colored. And come back next week to see another reworked page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colored Pages 2, 3, 4, and 8 (Book 1)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:25:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlers-scene all done!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to get all the pages in this scene out of the way. This scene only ranges from 2 through 8 (seven pages). &lt;strong&gt;I feel less cringy about these &amp;ldquo;flashback&amp;rdquo; pages now that they&amp;rsquo;re colored &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the text boxes look cleaner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The featured images above are the parts of the pages I like the most, but I sense, as I look back over the pages, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming back to touch up the coloring. No doubt the pages look better with color, but I see parts that could use a little polish. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; rushing a little when I did these. &lt;strong&gt;Pretty backgrounds require a bit of patience, you know?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;behind-the-scenes-update&#34;&gt;Behind the scenes update&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, so I said I would post colored Book 1 pages until the first post in March and then announce further news about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing behind the scenes. So here&amp;rsquo;s the update&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-book-2&#34;&gt;About Book 2&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing some writer&amp;rsquo;s block.&lt;/strong&gt; I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten much further with the current pages that are in progress (35 and 36). It&amp;rsquo;s clear from my work on all these Book 1 pages (some of which required redrawing some areas) that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem of wanting to draw at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon further reflection, it dawned on me that my primary motivation for drawing all these pages was my excitement for an upcoming scene in the story. &lt;strong&gt;So if I can reignite my excitement for the ending of Book 2, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to finish these current pages and continue the story!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; excited right now?! Good question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m just dreading having to make final decisions about the plot. I like to create lots of loose ends and I get anxious about tying them up just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never experienced this kind of writer&amp;rsquo;s block for Book 1 and it didn&amp;rsquo;t dawn on me until recently why that is. &lt;strong&gt;With Book 1, I drew out ALL the possible scenes in sequential order.&lt;/strong&gt; I ended up drawing thumbnails for&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;130 pages?&lt;/em&gt; This was before I shortened the storyline to 74 pages, but it helped me figure out how I wanted the story to go. I could visualize all the scenes I wanted and how/why they came about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Book 2, I skipped drawing out the whole story line, b/c I was already sure of how it would start.&lt;/strong&gt; I just wanted to dive in and figure out the rest of the plot as I went along. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m approaching the last scene I&amp;rsquo;m more certain about, I feel anxious about the &amp;ldquo;gray areas&amp;rdquo; coming up that I need to decide on and when I get anxious, I tend to freeze up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SO THERE. I need to draw out the scenes of Book 2.&lt;/strong&gt; I actually started doing that and it&amp;rsquo;s going very well! My goal is to get to the end of Book 2 with a more detailed idea of the sequence of events. Then some scene that I draw roughly will get me &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; excited to continue drawing pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-meantime&#34;&gt;In the meantime&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep coloring Book 1 pages! I already have a third of the pages done (maybe not uploaded yet) and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the momentum going away. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just plan on continuing posting colored pages through the end of May, after which I&amp;rsquo;ll take a month-long break.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll keep figuring out the story of Book 2 and hope that I can continue the story after that break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out pages &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-03/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-04/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-08/&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;! Next week will just be a single page, but a lot has changed on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 7 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wolf&#34;&gt;Wolf!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with this redone page! I was originally just going to fill in the existing line work digitally, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too sure with the result, so I redrew Wolf. It looks &lt;em&gt;SO&lt;/em&gt; much better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-following-changes-were-made-to-page-7&#34;&gt;The following changes were made to page 7:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew panel 1 (kept the same glow lines).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colored whole page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew text boxes and updated text box fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated sound effect in panel 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the new page 7 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;Next week, I look forward to doing something a little different than the usual,&lt;/strong&gt; so don&amp;rsquo;t forget to come back and check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-the-chase&#34;&gt;Back to the chase!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only part of this page that needed fixing was the very last panel.&lt;/strong&gt; I had no problem with how I drew Errie tripping over a tree stump, but the lines in her jeans coincided with the lines in the panel above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the tips I learned from an artist I follow online is that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid what he called &amp;ldquo;tangent lines&amp;rdquo; between panels, so that the lines don&amp;rsquo;t stop a person&amp;rsquo;s eyes from moving around the page.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure enough, the more I looked at this page, the more my eyes stopped at that intersection above this panel. &lt;strong&gt;So I endeavored to modify it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-one-thing-leads-to-another&#34;&gt;But one thing leads to another&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my best to work with the existing linework and save the panel. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But alas!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing I tried sat right with me, so I resorted to redrawing the whole panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid finicking too long on the details, I opted for a silhouette in this panel. Now, after coloring the page, I have no regrets. &lt;strong&gt;It looks awesome!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed tangent lines before, but never with a complete redrawing. &lt;strong&gt;It usually only takes small modification&lt;/strong&gt;, but so much is happening on this page that proved challenging in all my attempts to fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh well&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out all of page 29 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I&amp;rsquo;ll feature one of the first ten pages of Book 1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; And have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;definitely-needed-to-revise-this-page&#34;&gt;Definitely needed to revise this page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was finalizing the character design for Nascha. I felt so certain about the hair style
I gave her. &lt;strong&gt;Now, 2 years later, I look at this page and think that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;
to curb one&amp;rsquo;s style choices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I changed Nascha&amp;rsquo;s hair. I like how her bangs frame her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-important-rule-for-text-in-comics&#34;&gt;An important rule for text in comics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most jarring feature of this page were the walls of text.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel less bad about this cringe-worthy
mistake, since it&amp;rsquo;s apparently a common one made by artists new to drawing comics.
And besides, the stuff that
Nascha says in those walls of text wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to convey any helpful information. It was meant to be
mysterious and not well understood by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That goal didn&amp;rsquo;t change since I drew this page, but after 2
years, I see the disadvantage of having all this text taking up whole panels:
&lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no clear direction to the reader on how to interpret what is going on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is someone talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do I start reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Reads it] &lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;Did I just waste five minutes reading redundant information?!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page makes more sense once Errie starts talking, but I knew it can do better. Therefore, I did away
with the walls of text and created new speech bubbles. &lt;strong&gt;Now, in addition to clarifying what Nascha is saying,
I&amp;rsquo;m introducing a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; mystery in the situation&amp;mdash;the presence of &lt;em&gt;two kinds&lt;/em&gt; of speech bubbles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to the audience to figure out what this means, as the significance will be revealed by the
plot. In fact, you can find some hints in Book 2&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22/&#34;&gt;Check out the rest of page 22!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll post another updated page, one that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; proud of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>