<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book2 on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/book2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book2 on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 11:25:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/categories/book2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 43</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 11:25:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-43/</guid>
      <description>And the police station finally picks up&amp;mdash;!
Oh.
Hi there&amp;hellip;
Last Page of 2019 Two weeks from now I&amp;rsquo;ll start my month-long break from making comic pages, therefore this is the last page update for Book 2 until I return. However, next week I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the Book 1 pages I&amp;rsquo;ve been finishing. I&amp;rsquo;ll also post a small Christmas doodle.
Out of the 17 pages I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to finish by December, I have 12 finished, so five more are left!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 42</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 09:17:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-42/</guid>
      <description>Bye Morphics! It was nice knowing &amp;lsquo;ya!
Book 2 Progress Good news! I finished the last 2 new pages for the year!
That leaves 4 pages in the buffer currently &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;m going to post page 43 in 2 weeks and hold the rest until after my December break is over. Therefore, the next page update will be the last new page of the year!
Book 1 Progress After finishing those Book 2 pages, I continued lighting and shading more Book 1 pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 41</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 08:50:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-41/</guid>
      <description>Huh, where did Errie&amp;rsquo;s mom go? Hmmmmmm&amp;hellip;
Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll find out on the next page&amp;hellip;? We&amp;rsquo;ll see in 2 weeks, I guess.
Book 2 progress Good news! Since the last post, I finished 4 new pages! So in addition to the page in this post, I have 3 pages in the buffer. That covers the next two posts before I go on break in December!
I still have two more pages shade and light before the end of this month and I expect to get those done this coming week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 40</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 07:37:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-40/</guid>
      <description>AH!
It&amp;rsquo;s a HAND&amp;hellip;!
&amp;hellip;
So glad I could reveal this part of the story, despite the suspense it creates. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself a fan of horror movies, but I wanted to weave some kind of thriller-suspense into the plot.
&amp;hellip;Not a lot of it, of course. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this story for people like me, who wimp out at the sight of creepy hands, creepy clowns, and bloody weapons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 39</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 12:32:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-39/</guid>
      <description>Tenti is super absorbent.
In other news&amp;hellip;
Book 2 Status I got done with page 39, as you can see. I also finished page 40. I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished pages 41 and 42 yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to&amp;hellip;work it in. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain in the next paragraph.
I ignored Book 1 rework this week I ran into a bit of artist&amp;rsquo;s block this week, so I chose to cut back the workload to only pages 39 and 40 of Book 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 38</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 10:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-38/</guid>
      <description>Looks like these Morphics have a lot to catch up on!
Book 2 Progress update I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with page 39, so that will be ready to post for the next update! I&amp;rsquo;m also hoping to be done with 40 through 42 at the end of next week. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll start drawing the last batch of pages before the holidays, pages 43 through 46.
Book 1 Progress update All that&amp;rsquo;s left now to finish Book 1 are one or both of two steps per page: lighting/shading and finalizing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 37</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 09:05:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-37/</guid>
      <description>New faces! Meet Meppie and Stella!
Despite their small roles in the story, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to introducing them&amp;mdash;Meppie in particular. I like Meppie. She&amp;rsquo;s my kind of hero&amp;hellip;calm and collected, even in emergencies.
&amp;hellip;Most emergencies.
She appears a little alarmed on this page, but that just says something about the situation.
Where I am at with Book 1 I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with coloring in the base colors of all the pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 36</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 10:25:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-36/</guid>
      <description>Vix to the Rescue! &amp;hellip;Maybe?
&amp;lsquo;Guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the next page update.
Quick update For Book 2, the next 2 pages are finished and ready to post in the upcoming weeks! I also started a new batch of pages this week (pages 39 through 42).
For Book 1, I&amp;rsquo;m currently working away at covering each uncolored page in base colors. The remaining number is down to roughly 20 pages (out of about 30-ish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 35</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 09:17:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-35/</guid>
      <description>The mighty Catius fights Squid Lady!!! And then he&amp;rsquo;s caught&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;uh oh.
Another page up as promised! Last month has been busy! I&amp;rsquo;m almost finished with the next 3 pages in Book 2. I also got done flatting 16 pages in Book 1! Those are all the remaining pages that still needed needed it. This month I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on applying local colors to all pages that haven&amp;rsquo;t been colored yet&amp;hellip;as well as starting another batch of Book 2 pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 34</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 13:10:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-34/</guid>
      <description>Catius: MWEWRREOWRR
Translator: &amp;ldquo;Pass the ketchup, please.&amp;rdquo;
Translator: Uh, wait&amp;hellip;
Hope you like this pouncing cat! As you can see from the previous post, Catius and his glow not only breaks out of the panel, but also extends across the lower part of page 33!
I really had fun with this page once I figured out what should happen on it. I had a general idea, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure on the specifics, really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 33</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 10:45:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-33/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming&amp;hellip; But at last, page 33 is DONE!
In addition, I finished page 34 this morning, so it&amp;rsquo;s ready to be uploaded next week!
This calls for a victory dance!
And here&amp;rsquo;s a quick link to page 32 if you need a refresher on what the previous page looks like.
So what took me so long? Good question. In January, I struggled to find motivation to draw pages 33 and 34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 32</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 13:49:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</guid>
      <description>YAY I DID IT!
This one took me a while! Can you tell??? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t talk myself out of having to draw the water, it was required by the plotline.
But at least now one of Tenti&amp;rsquo;s abilities is pretty obvious&amp;hellip;and hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s obvious what&amp;rsquo;s NOT her ability. No &amp;ldquo;FSSHH&amp;rdquo; sounds while she&amp;rsquo;s running is a dead giveaway.
Well, time for a break. Here&amp;rsquo;s the plan. I still have a lot of pages ahead of me to complete Book 2, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking as good of a break as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 31</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 17:18:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-31/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for the really late update!
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot to balance this week, including how to proceed as far as uploading pages goes. I thought long an hard on this particular topic and I came to a decision. After I upload page 32, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin my break from drawing pages, to be resumed the beginning of January.
My main two reasons for choosing to take a break early consist of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 30</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 20:05:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</guid>
      <description>So excited right now.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a LONG time to draw this lady. I&amp;rsquo;m even more excited about showing next week&amp;rsquo;s page!
Thanks for reading! Come back next week for another look at the new character! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 29</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 11:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</guid>
      <description>Errie is ready to go!
Also, that stone&amp;hellip;I tend to forget about it!
It&amp;rsquo;s like one of those little details that you know is important but its ability to keep your interest wanes after a while&amp;hellip; Like in Book 1, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember to show Errie putting it in her pocket. She basically picked it up and forgot all about it and I totally forgot about it until planning for Errie to find it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 28</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 09:29:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</guid>
      <description>It took almost 30 pages for Errie to realize something&amp;rsquo;s wrong.
But the pace picks up yet again!
Building up a Buffer I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on the next two pages. Although I fully expect to have next week&amp;rsquo;s page done in time to upload, I made a goal to build up my buffer of pages again.
Holidays are coming up and I want to try drawing up enough pages to give me a few weeks&amp;rsquo; break from drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 27</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:52:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</guid>
      <description>So while finalizing the script on this page, a familiar song came to mind: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a Believer&amp;rdquo;, written by Neil Diamond and sung by the Monkees. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop laughing.
Also, NEW CHARACTER APPEARANCE! This will be fun&amp;hellip; [hehehe]
Sorry for late update I&amp;rsquo;ve been crazy busy lately. Starting this week, I&amp;rsquo;ll be resuming a 2-page-per-week production schedule to build my page buffer up again. My goal is to get enough pages stored up to cover more than a month of weekly page updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 26</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:35:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</guid>
      <description>Catius is really proud of his skillz.
Check out this week&amp;rsquo;s extra post! Part 3 of &amp;ldquo;How I Draw&amp;rdquo; is up!
2 years ago, I only got to this stage in page production. Believe me, it&amp;rsquo;s a relief to finally get to color these pages. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about my progress on coloring pages next week, but I hope you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying this glimpse into my drawing process.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing this comic for two years between college semesters, summer classes, and a part-time job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 25</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</guid>
      <description>YAY FOR CATZZZZZZZZZ
Keeping this brief: I have ONE PAGE in my buffer! Boy, am I getting places&amp;hellip;
And continuing with celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday&amp;hellip;
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out this week&amp;rsquo;s SPECIAL POST: How I Draw, Part 2
Thanks for reading! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 24</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:07:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</guid>
      <description>Behold&amp;hellip;CAT MORPHICS
MEOW
&amp;hellip;also, cats are kind of hard to draw&amp;hellip;
Happy Birthday, Morphic! About two years ago, I launched &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; and posted the first 8 pages of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; Book 1 on a Facebook page. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact date, but I remember drawing these first pages in August, hurrying to get them done by the end of the month, then posting them on the first weekend of September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 23</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 22:38:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</guid>
      <description>OUT INTO THE SUN AT LAST!
I got two more pages drawn and inked this week&amp;mdash;YAY! I expect to have those done by the end of next week.
Colored Page 15 is up! Check out page 15 of Book 1 to see the new changes!
Also, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this is a local server issue when I &amp;lsquo;test run&amp;rsquo; the post, but in case it is also an issue with the public-side of the website&amp;hellip;well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 22</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:21:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</guid>
      <description>DUN DUN DUN
Aaaaaaand scene. I&amp;rsquo;m letting the suspense sit for a while. In the meantime, we&amp;rsquo;re going check out what the other characters are up to&amp;hellip;
Yet another busy week! You guessed it, no new colored pages in Book 1 this week. I am even busier than last week, it seems. Lots of new stuff coming up and limited access to wifi didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Thankfully, this page buffer helps me to not worry about new pages for Book 2, since I still have new pages ready for the next two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 21</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 09:43:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</guid>
      <description>YYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYeah. Something&amp;rsquo;s up.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week I got two more pages colored like I expected to, so my page buffer is now up to 3 pages, as predicted. However, that was all I was I able to finish this week.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have another Book 1 page ready to update, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have better luck next week.
Until then&amp;hellip;
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to see the last page of this scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 20</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 20:38:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-20/</guid>
      <description>WELL UH OH
Things are about to get interesting&amp;hellip;again.
Taking it easy I decided to take a break from drawing last week, so now as of today, my buffer consists of only two pages. OH WELL.
Good news is, I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of coloring 2 more pages, so I anticipate having a 3-page buffer after next week&amp;rsquo;s update.
Another colored page in Book 1 Check out page 27 !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 19</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 11:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-19/</guid>
      <description>Dancing around the question. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so many investigation dramas, but making one is pretty fun.
Another Colored Page Check out page 16 of Book 1!
If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering how I&amp;rsquo;m choosing which pages to work on, basically I&amp;rsquo;m starting out with the pages that need the most alteration. Thus, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot of pages at the beginning of Book 1 refinished first before those in the last half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 18</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 07:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-18/</guid>
      <description>The sheriff makes another appearance.
He&amp;rsquo;s probably curious about some word changes I just made on some pages. I replaced &amp;lsquo;heatstroke&amp;rsquo; with &amp;lsquo;dehydration&amp;rsquo; on pages 14 and 16 of Book 2. See, I didn&amp;rsquo;t read up on what heatstroke was until I uploaded the page. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say it implies more of a life- and-death situation than I&amp;rsquo;d like (think &amp;lsquo;coma&amp;rsquo;&amp;mdash;I slap myself for not looking harder at the &amp;lsquo;stroke&amp;rsquo; side of &amp;lsquo;heatstroke&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 17</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 18:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-17/</guid>
      <description>Ooooooooooooooooooooooooo
Something&amp;rsquo;s clearly up. Who listens to the radio while switching loads?
{cough} {cough} SARCASM {cough}
Anyway long time no see, Lane One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked about drawing Lane is how easy her hairstyle is to draw. Or at least it feels that way. I never had to use a photo reference for it.
In contrast, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that having references for drawing Errie and her mother&amp;rsquo;s hair more realistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 16</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 11:31:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-16/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, Chan looks surprised.
End of scene Hope you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying the story so far! Come back next week to see the start of the next scene. We&amp;rsquo;ll get to see what Lane is up to.
Page 9 of Book 1 is now in color! Check it out here!
Thanks for reading! And have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 15</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:46:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-15/</guid>
      <description>The Burning Question Errie&amp;rsquo;s a little surprised to be regaining her mother&amp;rsquo;s trust so quickly.
A Small update Before last week, I was producing two colored pages per week for Book 2, with the intent of reaching a buffer of 8 pages. Since last week, I decided to slow down to producing one page per week, settling for a buffer of 5 pages.
&amp;hellip;Or, rather 3 pages currently. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the two latest pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 14</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:08:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-14/</guid>
      <description>Well darn&amp;hellip; Aw, heck. Who needs emergency services anyway?
Also&amp;hellip;
SURPRISE! I said last week that I might have a redrawn and colored page for Book 1. I am happy to announce&amp;hellip; I have two!
Check out pages 1 and 37!
Thanks for reading! Check out next week&amp;rsquo;s page update to find out what happens and maybe&amp;mdash;maybe&amp;mdash;you&amp;rsquo;ll get to see another redone page from Book 1! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 13</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 16:51:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-13/</guid>
      <description>HUH&amp;hellip; Nothing like a see-through, walk-through tiger in the kitchen to make one question her own senses.
Quick Status! Book 2 page buffer is still growing. Yay!
I decided to redraw and color one of the Book 1 pages and now that it&amp;rsquo;s done, it&amp;rsquo;s uploaded! Check out page 5!
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to see the next page of book 2! And who knows, there could be another colored/updated page of book 1&amp;hellip;maybe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 12</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 10:45:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-12/</guid>
      <description>Yeah Mom, get off the phone Smartphones are so distracting, you know? It keeps people from noticing things going on around them, including the important stuff&amp;hellip;such as when there&amp;rsquo;s a tiger in the kitchen.
Status Update I&amp;rsquo;m making good progress on growing my page buffer. So far I&amp;rsquo;m finished with pages up to page 16, which covers about a month of weekly updates (yay!). I&amp;rsquo;m also starting to chip away at the rework of some of the pages for Book 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 11</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:04:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-11/</guid>
      <description>WHOA Errie, was that your stomach growling?
It&amp;rsquo;s times like this, when I really look forward to drawing Book 2&amp;hellip;
[Sinister chuckling]
Come back next week to find out what&amp;rsquo;s in the kitchen! Thanks for reading! And have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 10</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-10/</guid>
      <description>The fox is in I like how Errie&amp;rsquo;s mom came out in panel 5. Really shows her protective side.
I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of coloring the next two pages, so I plan on uploading page 11 next week as planned.
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to find out what happens on the next page. Have a good Memorial Day weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 9</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:14:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-09/</guid>
      <description>Doodling Capri is the best.
Early Update I&amp;rsquo;m going out of town this week, so I&amp;rsquo;m posting this page today. I finished page 10 as expected, so I have no worries about posting it on time next week. Yay for meeting deadlines!
Anyways, now we get more of an explanation about the jar referenced in the last page of Book 1.
Thanks for reading! Next week&amp;rsquo;s page will have a change in pace, so remember to come back and check out what happens!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 8</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 23:51:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-08/</guid>
      <description>Definitely proud of this page&amp;mdash;especially the last panel.
All done! School is officially over for me and I got to draw a bunch this week. I just got page 9 done, so next week&amp;rsquo;s page is ready to upload. I&amp;rsquo;m also nearly done with page 10.
However, even though summer is here, I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much time on my hands because I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to working more. (It helps that I do not have classes, har har.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 7</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 07:50:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-07/</guid>
      <description>NICE TAIL CHAN So proud of his expression in panel 5.
Almost done with the semester! I&amp;rsquo;m itching to get done with my schoolwork so that I can get back into drawing more pages.
Also, in case you missed my unscheduled announcement earlier this week, you can now make comments on my posts through Disqus! As I understand it, you do have to create a free account with Disqus in order to comment, but it&amp;rsquo;s FREE and you can comment on any site that uses Disqus and that includes a lot of sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 6</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 22:03:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-06/</guid>
      <description>Where have we seen this guy before&amp;hellip;? Oh yeah&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s Chan! The kid who skipped out on going to the festival with his friends and thereby ended up missing out on an exciting (and slightly terrifying) adventure in the woods.
YEP. That&amp;rsquo;s him!
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing a lot more of him in this book&amp;hellip; [cackles quietly and ominously]
In other news The next two pages actually took the most time to produce out of all my colored pages so far!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 5</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 18:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-05/</guid>
      <description>Gosh&amp;hellip;some days it feels like I go overboard on these inks, but talk about shading a darkened room!
However, I do really like how the color-shading pops out in this page.
Status Update: Buffer Complete! Every weekly update from now until the end of finals week is finished and ready to upload. As I wrap up this semester I&amp;rsquo;ll upload these posts, but I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on drawing more pages until I&amp;rsquo;m close to done with school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 17:23:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-04/</guid>
      <description>And now back to our protagonist!
I&amp;rsquo;m going to miss drawing these landscapes. They were super easy and very pretty!
Short Update I didn&amp;rsquo;t stick with the daily posts of fox videos this week. I got really busy and I kept forgetting.
However, based on previous experience, I never really got much reaction on those video posts. Therefore, I think I should just stick to posting a few videos every now and then, instead of a whole week of daily posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:29:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-03/</guid>
      <description>A great reminder to not run drowsy&amp;hellip;especially if you run fast.
Guess what I forgot last week Remember that last week we saw Vix transform? Remember what I usually do when we see a Morphic transform for the first time in the story? That&amp;rsquo;s right&amp;mdash;It&amp;rsquo;s video-sharing time! Featuring foxes!
Without further ado&amp;hellip;
WHAT DOES THE FOX SAY
Thanks for reading! I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting more fox videos on my Facebook page throughout the week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 22:12:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-02/</guid>
      <description>Hmmm&amp;hellip;where have we seen that wolf before&amp;hellip;?
And oh yeah, now we know the Fox is a she.
Short Post I&amp;rsquo;m a little busy this weekend, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just give a quick status update. I have pages finished up to page 6 now&amp;mdash;WOW. I was on fire this week with pages 5 and 6. If I can manage to get the next two done next week, I&amp;rsquo;m set for the rest of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 22:01:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-01/</guid>
      <description>First colored Morphic page ever! Welcome back from the intermission! Hope you like the new character and the new coloring style.
I managed to finish coloring page 2 and now I&amp;rsquo;m coloring pages 3 and 4 (got all the other drawing for those pages done and only the coloring is left).
I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with my progress so far, but now Spring Break is over and I have to buckle down for the second half of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>