<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Morphic</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-author&#34;&gt;The Author&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My name is Maria Rice&lt;/strong&gt; and I am a web developer by trade
with a passion for reading web comics, graphic novels, comic
books, etc. &lt;strong&gt;And I enjoy comics so much that I make one of
my very own!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-plot&#34;&gt;The Plot&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Erica &amp;ldquo;Errie&amp;rdquo; Bright, a regular teenaged girl who
discovers the existence of powerful beings called Morphics
just outside her hometown of Ash Root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-morphics&#34;&gt;What are &amp;lsquo;Morphics&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerful beings with the ability to switch between either of
two forms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That of an animal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That which is similar to a human, but with some animal
features corresponding to their animal form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Morphic can have more abilities in addition to his/her
transformation ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the first finished plot line for &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; in the
spring of 2016. I posted the first drawn pages in September
of that same year and have been uploading pages weekly ever
since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; was going to be a 5-book series, but after
discovering how much time and effort it takes to produce
one book, I changed it to a 3-book series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;medium&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I hope to gradually add color to the pages as the
project grows, for now I show it in the original black and
white to keep the story going. I draw the pages with black
ink pen and add the speech bubbles with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-visiting&#34;&gt;Thanks For Visiting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With immense gratitude, I welcome you to view my work and
leave some constructive feedback. I hope you enjoy the story
as much as I enjoy creating it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 30</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 20:05:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So excited right now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a LONG time to draw this lady. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; excited about
showing next week&amp;rsquo;s page!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week for another look at the new character! Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 29</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 11:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Errie is ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also, that &lt;strong&gt;stone&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip;I tend to forget about it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like one of those little details that you know is
important but its ability to keep your interest wanes after
a while&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;Like in Book 1, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember to show
Errie putting it in her pocket.&lt;/strong&gt; She basically picked it up
and forgot all about it and &lt;strong&gt;I &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; forgot&lt;/strong&gt; about it
until planning for Errie to find it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk about &amp;lsquo;confusing the audience&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; I knew I had to
supply some kind of explanation for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;obvious unexplained
gap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the timeline of the stone&amp;rsquo;s appearances, since I
failed to make it clear. Best fix I could think of was for
Errie to spell it out. Still, having some kind of visual
evidence of the stone being put in her pocket would have
been better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the nice thing is, I haven&amp;rsquo;t reworked some of those
pages yet at that point in the plot, so I &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be able to
squeeze in an extra panel to convey where the stone ends up
&amp;hellip;we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt silly enough about this little goof-up to make &lt;strong&gt;one
of my major goals in Book 2 to show clearly &lt;em&gt;when Errie
has the stone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s usually
going to be in her pocket, but &lt;em&gt;now you know&lt;/em&gt; she remembered to
take it with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s my rant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to see what happens next! &lt;strong&gt;Believe me, you
&lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; want to miss it!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of the next page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 28</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 09:29:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It took almost &lt;em&gt;30&lt;/em&gt; pages for Errie to realize something&amp;rsquo;s
wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the pace picks up yet again!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-up-a-buffer&#34;&gt;Building up a Buffer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on the next two pages. Although I fully
expect to have next week&amp;rsquo;s page done in time to upload, &lt;strong&gt;I
made a goal to build up my buffer of pages again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holidays are coming up and I want to try drawing up enough
pages to give me a few weeks&amp;rsquo; break from drawing. I would
still upload pages (except the week before Christmas, which
is an art upload), but I think I need some time off from
drawing around that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have more time than before Book 2 to work on
these pages, I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to feel &amp;lsquo;fatigue&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;nothing too
bad, but &lt;em&gt;I noticed it&amp;rsquo;s gotten a bit harder to motivate me
to draw.&lt;/em&gt; Having deadlines helps me in this case, but I know
I need to rest, so &lt;strong&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll aim for taking a break
during the holiday season.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, taking time off from &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo; will help me keep
going with it. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to find out what Errie&amp;rsquo;s doing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:54:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 4 of my drawing process!
We are now at the final post dedicated to showing how I
create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out
page 27! Just click the link to go back a page to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-4-color-stage&#34;&gt;Part 4: Color Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I talked about using GIMP to turn my pages from
image files to layered lines and text. This week I’m talking
about my coloring process and creating the final image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-open-file-and-apply-settings&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open file and apply settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set the image mode from ‘Greyscale’ to ‘RGB’. An image
set to the former will not show color, even when you paint
with a selected color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-flatting&#34;&gt;Step 2: Flatting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where my process seems a little counter-intuitive.
I color the areas of the page with &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo; colors before
filling them in with their true colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easier to go back and change the color of something,
like Vix’s coat. If I realize I used the wrong shade of red,
I can select Vix’s coat in all panels of the page by using
the ‘Select By Color’ tool and fill in all areas with the
correct color.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: While it is true I could select by color with the
true colors, if something other than Vix’s coat is the
same red, those areas will be selected too. Selection is
simpler when these areas are distinguished and this
distinguishment is possible by flatting these areas in
different colors on a different layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hear that flatting leads to more efficient coloring time.
Basically I’m filling in the areas to select before even
deciding what color these areas are going to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the flatting process. It’s like coloring a
coloring book without caring about the color combination.
It’s very refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;I create a layer underneath the lines layer and fill
in areas one color at a time, unselecting those areas by
color so that I don’t paint over them accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-3-add-true-colors&#34;&gt;Part 3: Add True Colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the easy part of the coloring process. Now that I
have my flats layer, I only have to Select By Color on that
layer and fill in all those areas on another layer (under
the lines layer) with the true color. I don’t like creating
a lot of unnecessary layers, so I would typically create
two, one for foreground and one for background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use the same colors I used before on previous
pages, I open up the necessary files and use the ‘Color
Picker’ tool to select the true color and fill in the areas
on the current file with that color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I add whatever colors I want. I often use
gradients (color blends) for the backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-4-shading-brights&#34;&gt;Part 4: Shading/Brights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LAST STEP!&lt;/strong&gt; This step is a little longer than it looks…
First I create two layers, one for shading and one for
highlights. Then I add a layer mask to each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what’s a layer mask?&lt;/strong&gt; It’s like another layer, but it
controls the transparency of the visible layer it’s
attached to. I use it mostly to add gradient effects in
the shading/brights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently use a shade of blue-green for shading and pure
white for highlights. I paint with these colors directly
on the layers and adjust their transparency on the layer’s
corresponding mask to make them semi-transparent so that
the true colors below them to show up a little, giving
the illusion of depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-just-kidding-this-is-really-the-last-step&#34;&gt;Step 5: Just kidding, this is really the last step…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah! We need to export this thing. Right now the file
is still not an image file you can upload to the internet.
It is still a .xcf file, which is only displayable in GIMP.
I have to export it to .jpg format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ‘File-&amp;gt;Export as…’, use default settings, and &lt;em&gt;WHA-LA!&lt;/em&gt;
The image appears in the specified folder!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;And all these substeps take me about 2 hours on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this little run-through of how I make
pages. Feel free to try out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;!
It’s helpful for me and
I recommend it for basic image-layer editing. You could
draw from scratch on it if you wanted to. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it,
but I personally find that I draw way better traditionally
than by computer, so I only use it for simple things like
outlines, speech bubbles, text, and select-and-fill style
coloring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other possible software you could use for digital drawing
include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adobe Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clip Studio/Manga Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, I’ll get off my soapbox now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HAPPY BIRTHDAY MORPHIC!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m done celebrating now. Thanks again for reading and
have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 27</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:52:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So while finalizing the script on this page, a familiar song
came to mind: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a Believer&amp;rdquo;, written by Neil Diamond and
sung by the Monkees. &lt;strong&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop laughing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEW CHARACTER APPEARANCE!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This will be fun&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;[hehehe]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sorry-for-late-update&#34;&gt;Sorry for late update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been crazy busy lately. Starting this week, I&amp;rsquo;ll be
resuming a 2-page-per-week production schedule to build my
page buffer up again. My goal is to get enough pages stored
up to cover more than a month of weekly page updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not going to focus too much on updating Book 1 pages, but I
might post one soon that I stopped in the middle of coloring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend everybody! I&amp;rsquo;ll post next week&amp;rsquo;s page as
scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AND DON&amp;rsquo;T FORGET TO CHECK OUT THE &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/&#34;&gt;FINAL POST&lt;/a&gt;
OF How I Draw!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 3 of my drawing process!
We are now at the third of four posts dedicated to showing
how I create the pages of “Morphic”. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to check
out page 26!&lt;/strong&gt; Just click the left arrow icon to go back a
page and see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-text-stage&#34;&gt;Part 3: Text Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the drawing process starts to get techy. I use
a program called GIMP for adding text and color layers to
my pages. It’s like Photoshop except it’s open source and
managed by a community of developers. You can download it
free of charge &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-open-the-file&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open the file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin by starting GIMP and opening my scanned image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-create-layers&#34;&gt;Step 2: Create Layers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My image is automatically opens as its own layer. I add two
more layers&amp;ndash;one filled with white and one that stays
transparent. I put the white layer below all other layers
and the transparent one on top, sandwiching the scanned
image in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-single-out-lines&#34;&gt;Step 3: Single out lines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my goal&amp;ndash;I want to keep the lines visible, but be
able to see through the white spaces between them. There
are different ways of accomplishing this, but basically
what I do is select the whole area that’s black on the
image layer (only lines are selected, no white-space),
select the transparent layer, and fill the selection with
black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I hide the image layer, but the lines are still there.
If I hide the top/transparent layer, the lines disappear
and only white shows up. If I show that layer again and
hide the white layer, only the lines show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-crop-images&#34;&gt;Step 4: Crop Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create two new files that are copies of the original
layers file. Then I use a cropping tool to cut out the
parts I want&amp;mdash;the first page on the first file and the
second page on the second file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-add-text&#34;&gt;Step 5: Add Text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On each image file, I add editable text layers using the
‘Text’ tool and move them around. The typefaces I use are a
mix of my own custom-made fonts (using a free
typeface-generation website) and open-source fonts
available from Google. I mostly use one I had generated
based on my own handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-6-draw-speech-bubbles&#34;&gt;Step 6: Draw Speech Bubbles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a variety of selection tools and path tools to shape
the areas that become speech bubbles. After filling the
areas with white, I stroke with the paintbrush tool.
Sometimes I even do more than one bubbles layer, to get a
layering effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;edit-undo-is-my-friend&#34;&gt;‘Edit-&amp;gt;Undo’ is my friend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes order matters in the way I create speech bubbles
or anything else, so I frequently test changes and undo
those I don’t like. &lt;em&gt;Who doesn’t…?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three stages down, one to go! Check out next week’s posts
for the regular page update AND the post for Stage 4, the
COLORING STAGE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 26</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:35:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Catius is really proud of his skillz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-out-this-week-s-extra-post&#34;&gt;Check out this week&amp;rsquo;s extra post!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/&#34;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; of &amp;ldquo;How I Draw&amp;rdquo; is up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 years ago, I only got to this stage in page production.
Believe me, it&amp;rsquo;s a relief to finally get to color these
pages. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about my progress on coloring pages
next week, but I hope you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying this glimpse into my
drawing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing this comic for two years between
college semesters, summer classes, and a part-time job. Now
I&amp;rsquo;m graduated, I have a full time job, and now I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;coloring&lt;/strong&gt;
these pages! So much has changed and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to
revealing more of the story. One page at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to seeing Book 1 in full color,
but yeah. &lt;em&gt;One page at a time&amp;hellip;per week&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anyway&#34;&gt;Anyway&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out the extra post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:24:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 2 of my drawing process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now at the second of four posts dedicated to
showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. But don’t
worry&amp;ndash;page 25 is also posted! Just click the left
navigation button to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-ink-stage&#34;&gt;Part 2: Ink Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all four stages, this one is definitely the
shortest. It often takes me under an hour to ink one page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-prep&#34;&gt;Step 1: Prep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin by taping the pencil drawing onto a flat surface,
which is usually a table or clipboard. Then I tape a sheet
of tracing paper over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-inking&#34;&gt;Step 2: Inking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I draw with several sizes of black ink pen, but I typically
use size 005 for the main content of each page. The tracing
paper is thin enough for me to see the pencil lines through
it as I draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also gotten into the practice of drawing with my hand
on another sheet of paper on top of the tracing paper,
shifting it around as I draw. This is so that I don’t get
oil from my hands on the tracing paper because I noticed
early on that my inked lines didn’t look so great and they
looked far better when I started drawing with minimal skin
contact on the tracing paper. I’m guessing that the oil on
my hands was repelling the ink as it was drying and it
affected the quality of the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-scanning&#34;&gt;Step 3: Scanning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the drawing, I untape both the ink drawing
and the pencil drawing. I place the ink drawing in the
scanner and align the edges. Then I run the scanner with black and white
settings so that the image only contains straight black and
white pixels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have an image saved on my laptop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out next week’s posts for the regular page update AND the post for Stage 3, the text stage!
Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 25</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;YAY FOR CATZZZZZZZZZ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping this brief: I have ONE PAGE in my buffer! Boy, am I
getting places&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And continuing with celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out this week&amp;rsquo;s SPECIAL POST:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/&#34;&gt;How I Draw, Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-make-a-page&#34;&gt;How I Make a Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how digital art is made? Many
styles exist, as do many methods.
To celebrate two years of drawing “Morphic”, &lt;strong&gt;I’m happy to
share a glimpse into my drawing process&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a lot to
say about each stage, so I’ll be dedicating four separate
posts to cover how I make a page, &lt;strong&gt;one post for each stage&lt;/strong&gt;.
Regular page updates are still going and you can check them
out by pressing the back/forward icons or clicking a recent
post link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1-pencil-stage&#34;&gt;Part 1: Pencil Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hand-draw all my pages before coloring them digitally.
Here is how I start!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-thumbnail&#34;&gt;Step 1: Thumbnail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I draw my pages in two-page layouts. I start out with an
easy, messy sketch with scribbled scripts along the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-photos&#34;&gt;Step 2: Photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collect photos to use for reference. I didn’t use them as
much at the beginning of Book 1, but now I rely on them a
lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-initial-sketching&#34;&gt;Step 3: Initial Sketching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lightly sketch the panels and figures on regular 8.5” x
11” copy paper. I draw on copies of a template I made when
I first started Book 1, so that the dimensions of each page
is always the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-final-details&#34;&gt;Step 4: Final Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the longest, but very gratifying, part of the
pencil stage. It can take anywhere from one to two
hours…taking up most of the approximately 2 hours average
time I spend in the pencil stage for each single page of
“Morphic”! (approx. 4 hours for a two-page spread)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed this post! Come back next week to read
about the ink stage AND to see the next regular page update!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 24</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:07:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Behold&amp;hellip;CAT MORPHICS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MEOW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;also, cats are kind of hard to draw&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;happy-birthday-morphic&#34;&gt;Happy Birthday, Morphic!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two years ago, I launched &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; and posted the
first 8 pages of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; Book 1 on a Facebook page. I don&amp;rsquo;t
remember the exact date, but I remember drawing these first
pages in August, hurrying to get them done by the end of the
month, then posting them on the first weekend of September.
So I consider Sept 1st to be the birthday of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In celebration, I created extra posts that I&amp;rsquo;ll upload
alongside the regular page updates. These posts describe
my drawing process in &lt;strong&gt;4 stages&lt;/strong&gt;. Today&amp;rsquo;s post covers
stage 1, next week&amp;rsquo;s post will cover stage 2, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to read the first post for &amp;ldquo;How I Draw&amp;rdquo;? Follow the
link &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-other-news&#34;&gt;In other news&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no new colored Book 1 page this week. I&amp;rsquo;m
probably going to pause those updates until I&amp;rsquo;m done with
&amp;ldquo;How I Draw&amp;rdquo; posts. But I&amp;rsquo;m still going to work on them, so
I&amp;rsquo;ll post whatever I get done all at once after finishing the
extra posts celebrating the birthday of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did just post the last ready page in my buffer, BUT. I
I am in the middle of coloring the next two pages and I expect
to get them done this weekend (esp. since it&amp;rsquo;s a 3-day
weekend, hehe). Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;m confident I&amp;rsquo;ll have pages
ready for the next two regular page updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out next week&amp;rsquo;s posts for Stage 2 of my drawing process
and more conversation with THE CATS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great Labor Day weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 23</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 22:38:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OUT INTO THE SUN AT LAST!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got two more pages drawn and inked this week&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;YAY!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
I expect to have those done by the end of next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;colored-page-15-is-up&#34;&gt;Colored Page 15 is up!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-15/&#34;&gt;page 15 of Book 1&lt;/a&gt; to see
the new changes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;hoping&lt;/em&gt; this is a local server issue when I
&amp;lsquo;test run&amp;rsquo; the post, but in case it is also an issue with
the public-side of the website&amp;hellip;well. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say, try
as I might, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t re-orient page 15 of Book 1 into
portrait layout&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;which is WEIRD&lt;/strong&gt;. The file shows up in the
correct orientation and I open it in another app and it
displays correctly, but then I run the server and &lt;strong&gt;WHAT
the WHAT&lt;/strong&gt; is going on?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if it shows up that way when you browse to it, &lt;strong&gt;yeah,
that&amp;rsquo;s a bug&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll know about &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; one anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;please-let-me-know-if-you-notice-any-other-pages-displaying-wrong&#34;&gt;Please let me know if you notice any other pages displaying wrong&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first and only page I had issues with&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m wondering
if it&amp;rsquo;s a bug from an update. I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking into that, but
any feedback on Facebook or on the comments below (or Github, if
you fancy) is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; Fixed page 15! Looks like it was an OS problem
on my side. My image wasn&amp;rsquo;t displaying in its true orientation
except the times I worked on it in GIMP and uploaded it
to the site. I literally look at it in its file folder and on
other apps on my laptop and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be showing the image
in the same orientation as on GIMP or online.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; was confusing! I never had this issue before. I
did install a new version of GIMP and finished page 15 with
that version. Something must have changed in the way GIMP
exports image files.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OH WELL. Now I know what the problem is and how to prevent
it from now on.&lt;/strong&gt; (8/25/18)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to see who&amp;rsquo;s talking in that last panel!
Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting an extra something, celebrating
&lt;strong&gt;2 years&lt;/strong&gt; since I first started drawing &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;! Stay
tuned and have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 22</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:21:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DUN DUN DUN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aaaaaaand&lt;/em&gt; scene. I&amp;rsquo;m letting the suspense sit for a while.
&lt;strong&gt;In the meantime, we&amp;rsquo;re going check out what the other
characters are up to&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;yet-another-busy-week&#34;&gt;Yet &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; busy week!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You guessed it, no new colored pages in Book 1 this week. I
am even busier than last week, it seems. Lots of new stuff
coming up and limited access to wifi didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Thankfully,
this page buffer helps me to not worry about new pages for
Book 2, since I still have new pages ready for the next
two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I still have high hopes of having another colored
Book 1 page ready for  next week, since the one I&amp;rsquo;m working
on is actually almost finished. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t touch it
this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s all the more reason to check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get excited, because &lt;strong&gt;this upcoming scene will have &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;
 new characters!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait..!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 21</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 09:43:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;YYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYeah.&lt;/em&gt; Something&amp;rsquo;s up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-s-been-a-busy-week&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got two more pages colored like I expected to, so my page
buffer is now up to 3 pages, as predicted. However, that
was all I was I able to finish this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have another Book 1 page ready to update, but I
think I&amp;rsquo;ll have better luck next week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to see the last
page of this scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>