<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About &#34;Morphic&#34;</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about/</guid>
      <description>Author My name is Maria Rice and I make websites for a living. In my spare time, I like to read comics and graphic novels. I am a self-taught artist, with years of experience drawing in traditional ink and GIMP.
Plot A plea for help from a mysterious girl sidetracks Errie Bright* and Lane Valerie on their way to a local festival. Fooled at first by the expectation of seeing people dressed up for the same event, the girls soon realize that the people they meet in the woods that day are not in costume&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/new-website/</guid>
      <description>I feel great joy when I find I can reuse old content for something fun. Also, I got some practice on Clip Studio!
It&amp;rsquo;s here! This is the last post on this website, as I continue the Morphic webcomic&amp;rsquo;s posts and updates on the new website! Check it out!
Thanks for following! See you on the&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;otter side&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 60</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-60/</guid>
      <description>Huh. Lily goes through walls.
News about the current website Weeks ago, I looked into giving this site a custom domain name so that the url is easier to market. It turns out that the free hosting this site is on probably won&amp;rsquo;t let me remove &amp;lsquo;/morphic&amp;rsquo; from the end of it. So (using an example domain name) it may look like &amp;ldquo;example.com/morphic&amp;rdquo;, even though I want &amp;ldquo;example.com&amp;rdquo;.
In addition to that little complication, I came up against a nasty little bug with the links in the chapters section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 59</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-59/</guid>
      <description>One thing I wish I could convey more strongly in this page: Lily is not one who can be scared easily.
UPDATED PAGES AND NEW SPEECH BUBBLES Along with this new page, I have uploaded 5 more revised pages in Book 1! Two of them had not previously been colored.
Here are the pages:
 Page 13 Page 14 Page 15 Page 16 Page 17  New Font Family I also recently experimented with new font and speech bubbles, which I will now implement in my comic pages from this day forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 58</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-58/</guid>
      <description>Oh, I guess Errie is ok now&amp;hellip;
Also, this page fulfills the long-lived desire of mine to tie up some loose ends. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I mean, maybe try re-reading Book 2. :D
More Social Media I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot lately about next steps for Morphic and I came to the conclusion that it&amp;rsquo;s time I actually promote the webcomic more actively on social media. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting to add a link to Twitter, but here&amp;rsquo;s a link to my Instagram profile!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 57</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-57/</guid>
      <description>Everyone’s talking about death all of a sudden…
Almost finished with the next batch of pages I got a lot done these past two weeks! I began four more pages and already started coloring them. By the time I post the last page in my buffer (which comes right after today’s page), I’ll have 4 more to add to it, which should cover the page updates for another two months!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 56</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-56/</guid>
      <description>Introductions exchanged.
A new &amp;lsquo;first&amp;rsquo; I’ve had an interesting two weeks since my last post. I delivered my first-ever art commission! That was fun. I was a little nervous, but it turned out great.
Today I started drawing the next batch of new pages! I’ll share my progress on those pages with the next post.
In other news I had been using a work laptop to draw pages lately and now I&amp;rsquo;m switching to another device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 55</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-55/</guid>
      <description>I guess this means the Q &amp;amp; A session is over&amp;hellip;
So much stuff happening on this page! Including a proper intro for that tiger girl!
Welcome Back! And Happy 4th of July! During my very restful break, I got to do some casual sketching and writing&amp;hellip;and welcome home my very own kitten! MEOW.
This week I added a bunch of updates and fixes to the website!
 Website Updates There was apparently a routing bug in the archive section, but that&amp;rsquo;s fixed now and I renamed the section &amp;lsquo;Chapters&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 54</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-54/</guid>
      <description>Errie seizes the opportunity to ask some burning questions.
Next post scheduled for Sat, July 4th! Thanks for following the story for the last five months! I&amp;rsquo;m going to wrap up the next 4 pages this week and then take a 4-week break so that I can keep drawing without burnout for another five months.
A few thoughts on Book 1 printing My goal has always been to run a crowdfund campaign to have Book 1 printed as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s completely colored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 53</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-53/</guid>
      <description>Now Errie and Chan think that Wolf needs to take some lessons on etiquette, because &amp;ldquo;throwing&amp;rdquo; them into doors isn&amp;rsquo;t one of them.
It&amp;rsquo;s May! As promised, I have uploaded the newest wave of pages for Book 1! Check them out below!
  Page 1
  Page 2
  Page 9
  Page 10
  Page 11
  Page 12
  Goodbye Prologue In addition to these new pages, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I removed pages 3 through 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 52</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-52/</guid>
      <description>Wolf sure likes to zoom around a lot!
Still making progress on Book 1 Forgot to mention in my last post what my April goal is. I&amp;rsquo;m shading and finalizing six pages from the very beginning of Book 1! So far I have 2 out of 6 pages finalized and I expect to be done with those within a week. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll take a short break before starting on more pages for Book 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 51</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-51/</guid>
      <description>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s what kind of Morphic she is&amp;hellip;
This was actually my first time drawing vampire bats. It was fun!
Breaks are good! For almost a week, I got to work on something other than comic pages. I have a new website in the works that I started a while back and I got a lot done on it this week. There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot to do on it, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have it ready in a month or two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 50</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-50/</guid>
      <description>Chan shares a valid point as to why people shouldn&amp;rsquo;t run from every morphic in sight&amp;hellip;
Update on March Goal I finished the base colors of the next 4 pages! And they will all be shaded this coming week, so I should have page 51 posted on its scheduled day.
After that, I will take a week off from drawing before working on some Book 1 pages. The one lesson I&amp;rsquo;m taking away from this month is that I need to enforce short monthly breaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 49</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 10:31:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-49/</guid>
      <description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s where the &amp;lsquo;crash&amp;rsquo; came from&amp;hellip;
And look who&amp;rsquo;s back!
Funny, that they should bump into him there, heheh.
Quick update I managed to finish the &amp;lsquo;pencil&amp;rsquo; stage for pages 51 through 54 and I just have to print them out to start inking them. However, I was hoping to get more done before this post and I feel like I need a short break, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking today off and perhaps Monday as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 48</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:50:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-48/</guid>
      <description>Ouch. That&amp;rsquo;s gotta hurt.
Ooo, new character! &amp;hellip;with a creepy-looking mask.
oooOOOOOooooo
I had a lot of fun drawing this kid. I look forward to drawing him more!
Five more pages finalized! (Book 1) Three of them were colored last year, but I redid the cell-shading to match the newly-colored pages. Here are the five pages I updated:
 Page 25 Page 26 Page 27 Page 28 Page 29  In addition, I added some extra lettering to page 31 so that there are consistent sound effects across all these pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 47</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:18:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-47/</guid>
      <description>WHAT.
IS THAT.
Time to run&amp;hellip;again.
New character&amp;mdash;YAY! I had fun drawing this gal. Too bad it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hard to tell what kind of Morphic she is. It will make sense when you know it though. I have a name in mind for her, but I&amp;rsquo;m hesitating to announce it until I&amp;rsquo;m sure about it.
So for now, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll call her &amp;ldquo;the new girl&amp;rdquo;.
Book 1 Progress I am about half way through shading and lighting 5 out of the 6 pages I was hoping to have done by the end of this month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 46</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 09:54:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-46/</guid>
      <description>Ouch.
Poor Wolf&amp;hellip;verbal assault from teenagers is not fun.
January Goal Achieved! I finished pages 47 through 50 early! That gives me four pages in the buffer for February and March. I rewarded myself with a day dedicated to doing something different than the usual routine and then started on my February goal a few days early.
Progress begins for February goal I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to have six finalized pages for Book 1 by the end of February.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 45</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 07:47:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-45/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s WOLF!
I am thrilled to finally reveal his other form! I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to drawing him a lot more in the upcoming pages.
In addition, I am very proud of the gawking faces I drew in that last panel!
Current progress At the time of my last post, I had started the initial drawings of pages 47 through 50. Since then, I got the inking, text, and base coloring stages finished on all those pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 44</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 07:32:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-44/</guid>
      <description>Sounds like the &amp;ldquo;police&amp;rdquo; will be here any minute now. Hehehee&amp;hellip;
December Break is over! Welcome back! I hope you had a merry Christmas and a good start to the new year.
I, for one, had a very restful month off and got to spend time with family, which is great. Now I&amp;rsquo;m ready to dive back into the drawing comic pages!
Next Six Months First, I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue posting one page every 2 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2019</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2019/</guid>
      <description>I hope you had a Happy Thanksgiving!
It&amp;rsquo;s the moment you have been waiting for&amp;hellip;
Christmas Doodle! &amp;hellip;Heheh.
Ok, moving on to what you were really waiting for&amp;hellip;
I finalized 17 pages! They&amp;rsquo;re all in different sections of Book 1, so here are the links to each individual page that&amp;rsquo;s updated as of this post. Check &amp;lsquo;em out!
  Page 18
  Page 19
  Page 20</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 43</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 11:25:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-43/</guid>
      <description>And the police station finally picks up&amp;mdash;!
Oh.
Hi there&amp;hellip;
Last Page of 2019 Two weeks from now I&amp;rsquo;ll start my month-long break from making comic pages, therefore this is the last page update for Book 2 until I return. However, next week I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the Book 1 pages I&amp;rsquo;ve been finishing. I&amp;rsquo;ll also post a small Christmas doodle.
Out of the 17 pages I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to finish by December, I have 12 finished, so five more are left!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 42</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 09:17:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-42/</guid>
      <description>Bye Morphics! It was nice knowing &amp;lsquo;ya!
Book 2 Progress Good news! I finished the last 2 new pages for the year!
That leaves 4 pages in the buffer currently &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;m going to post page 43 in 2 weeks and hold the rest until after my December break is over. Therefore, the next page update will be the last new page of the year!
Book 1 Progress After finishing those Book 2 pages, I continued lighting and shading more Book 1 pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 41</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 08:50:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-41/</guid>
      <description>Huh, where did Errie&amp;rsquo;s mom go? Hmmmmmm&amp;hellip;
Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll find out on the next page&amp;hellip;? We&amp;rsquo;ll see in 2 weeks, I guess.
Book 2 progress Good news! Since the last post, I finished 4 new pages! So in addition to the page in this post, I have 3 pages in the buffer. That covers the next two posts before I go on break in December!
I still have two more pages shade and light before the end of this month and I expect to get those done this coming week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 40</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 07:37:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-40/</guid>
      <description>AH!
It&amp;rsquo;s a HAND&amp;hellip;!
&amp;hellip;
So glad I could reveal this part of the story, despite the suspense it creates. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself a fan of horror movies, but I wanted to weave some kind of thriller-suspense into the plot.
&amp;hellip;Not a lot of it, of course. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this story for people like me, who wimp out at the sight of creepy hands, creepy clowns, and bloody weapons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 39</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 12:32:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-39/</guid>
      <description>Tenti is super absorbent.
In other news&amp;hellip;
Book 2 Status I got done with page 39, as you can see. I also finished page 40. I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished pages 41 and 42 yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to&amp;hellip;work it in. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain in the next paragraph.
I ignored Book 1 rework this week I ran into a bit of artist&amp;rsquo;s block this week, so I chose to cut back the workload to only pages 39 and 40 of Book 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 38</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 10:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-38/</guid>
      <description>Looks like these Morphics have a lot to catch up on!
Book 2 Progress update I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with page 39, so that will be ready to post for the next update! I&amp;rsquo;m also hoping to be done with 40 through 42 at the end of next week. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll start drawing the last batch of pages before the holidays, pages 43 through 46.
Book 1 Progress update All that&amp;rsquo;s left now to finish Book 1 are one or both of two steps per page: lighting/shading and finalizing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 37</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 09:05:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-37/</guid>
      <description>New faces! Meet Meppie and Stella!
Despite their small roles in the story, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to introducing them&amp;mdash;Meppie in particular. I like Meppie. She&amp;rsquo;s my kind of hero&amp;hellip;calm and collected, even in emergencies.
&amp;hellip;Most emergencies.
She appears a little alarmed on this page, but that just says something about the situation.
Where I am at with Book 1 I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with coloring in the base colors of all the pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 36</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 10:25:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-36/</guid>
      <description>Vix to the Rescue! &amp;hellip;Maybe?
&amp;lsquo;Guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the next page update.
Quick update For Book 2, the next 2 pages are finished and ready to post in the upcoming weeks! I also started a new batch of pages this week (pages 39 through 42).
For Book 1, I&amp;rsquo;m currently working away at covering each uncolored page in base colors. The remaining number is down to roughly 20 pages (out of about 30-ish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 35</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 09:17:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-35/</guid>
      <description>The mighty Catius fights Squid Lady!!! And then he&amp;rsquo;s caught&amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;uh oh.
Another page up as promised! Last month has been busy! I&amp;rsquo;m almost finished with the next 3 pages in Book 2. I also got done flatting 16 pages in Book 1! Those are all the remaining pages that still needed needed it. This month I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on applying local colors to all pages that haven&amp;rsquo;t been colored yet&amp;hellip;as well as starting another batch of Book 2 pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update!</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/status-update-07-06-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 13:08:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/status-update-07-06-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! I hope you had a happy 4th of July!
As promised prior to my month-long break, I shall update you on how things are going from my end.
Where I&amp;rsquo;m at now This week, I finished the pencil stage for pages 35, 36, and 37 and started the pencil stage for page 38. I have also finished flatting 4 pages from Book 1.
As you can probably guess, I won&amp;rsquo;t have a page ready for posting next week&amp;mdash;or for the rest of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 34</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 13:10:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-34/</guid>
      <description>Catius: MWEWRREOWRR
Translator: &amp;ldquo;Pass the ketchup, please.&amp;rdquo;
Translator: Uh, wait&amp;hellip;
 Hope you like this pouncing cat! As you can see from the previous post, Catius and his glow not only breaks out of the panel, but also extends across the lower part of page 33!
I really had fun with this page once I figured out what should happen on it. I had a general idea, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure on the specifics, really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 33</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 10:45:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-33/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming&amp;hellip; But at last, page 33 is DONE!
In addition, I finished page 34 this morning, so it&amp;rsquo;s ready to be uploaded next week!
This calls for a victory dance!
 And here&amp;rsquo;s a quick link to page 32 if you need a refresher on what the previous page looks like.
So what took me so long? Good question. In January, I struggled to find motivation to draw pages 33 and 34.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 42 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:04:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42-rework/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s all the reworked pages&amp;hellip;for now! Thanks for your patience as I took time to figure out my writer&amp;rsquo;s/artist&amp;rsquo;s block. It&amp;rsquo;s been a weird experience for me to keep updating on a weekly basis without adding to the story line.
I hope you enjoyed reading my posts regarding changes to pages in Book 1! I reworked all the pages that required the most notable changes aside from coloring, so from here on out it should just be coloring that&amp;rsquo;s left to do on the rest of Book 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 41 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 14:17:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41-rework/</guid>
      <description>A Necessary Change Maybe I mentioned this before, but when I drew Capri as a goat for the first time in the story I drew him with a necklace, but then afterwards changed my mind. I was originally going to draw all morphics with their unique stones on necklaces, which they would wear around their neck.
Although the rationale isn&amp;rsquo;t revealed yet for why morphics have these stones on their chest, I&amp;rsquo;m ok with sharing the reason for the design change, since it isn&amp;rsquo;t really significant to the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 61 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 09:16:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61-rework/</guid>
      <description>This was a fun page! I enjoyed painting the galaxy background in the reworked panel. It was also fun to redraw the portrayal of the characters in the same panel&amp;mdash;The original silhouettes didn&amp;rsquo;t appear clear enough.
I made some progress on Book 2 pages Pages 33 and 34 are still underway, but I finished inking one and now I&amp;rsquo;m halfway inking the other.
My plan is to get these two pages done and upload them the two final weeks before I take my month-long break in June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 47 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:52:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47-rework/</guid>
      <description>Another cool page! Not much rework here, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to clean it up a bit!
&amp;hellip;
Well, not much else to say this week. But I finished another reworked page! So now I just need to finish content for two more updates.
Thanks for reading! Check out the complete page 47. Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll upload another reworked page that looks cool!
Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 60 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 11:20:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60-rework/</guid>
      <description>WOOOOOOOOOO I&amp;rsquo;m happy to finally experiment with coloring the inside of a blue door!
I might come back to this page when I figure out a style I like, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have some portrayal of what it looks like when someone goes into a blue door.
Still Writing Book 2&amp;rsquo;s plotline I think I&amp;rsquo;m making great progress! I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to figure out how a lot of the plot points lead into each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 38 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 12:07:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38-rework/</guid>
      <description>I Guess I Can Draw Goats Now I am so happy that I fixed Capri&amp;rsquo;s goat face in this page. I didn&amp;rsquo;t use any references to draw him! As a result, he looked less like a goat and more like a&amp;hellip;dog?
[Realizes an eerie resemblance to a former family pet.]
Well anyway&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a short update from behind-the-scenes. It had been many weeks since making any serious progress on Book 1 pages, but this week I finished one page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 36 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 18:24:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36-rework/</guid>
      <description>A Fun Experiment I am glad to be coloring Book 1 pages for many reasons. One of those reasons consists of an excuse to practice shading and lighting.
I&amp;rsquo;ve colored enough pages of Book 1 to figure out that my style needs to change in regards to lighting and shading. I started experimenting in some of these pages I uploaded recently, including this one. Here I stuck to using one color each for shading and light (and almost the same transparency across each layer), but allowing myself to &amp;lsquo;smudge&amp;rsquo; or blend the colors on each layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 35 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 18:31:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35-rework/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this page. Awesome colors! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with how well the backgrounds in the different panels complement each other.
Like a lot of pages in this scene, the rework on the inks involved fixing how I drew Capri. Although I deliberately made him a dislikable character, it&amp;rsquo;s bad when multiple panels of the character makes me grimace. I think I should have practiced drawing him a lot more before he appeared in the comic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 33 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 14:31:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33-rework/</guid>
      <description>Another week, another reworked page! Only one thing to say about this page&amp;mdash;Capri looks a lot more surprised without his mouth gaping open!
No other news except that I&amp;rsquo;m still making progress on sketching the plot of Book 2. I think it&amp;rsquo;s coming along pretty well, and I&amp;rsquo;m slowly growing more confident in the story line.
I did slow my pace on Book 1 production so that I can focus on other things, so next week&amp;rsquo;s page will be another reworked page!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 32 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32-rework/</guid>
      <description>Not a very interesting reworked page today, so how about some discussion?
You&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering how I&amp;rsquo;m choosing the order of pages to color, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that.
Gameplan: The First Sweep Perhaps I mentioned before, but I&amp;rsquo;m first hitting all the pages that clearly need ink rework. Since a high concentration of these pages are in the first half of the book, this means that the first half will look more &amp;lsquo;done&amp;rsquo; than the second half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 30 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 18:10:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</guid>
      <description>Splash! This page was a doozy! I spent a long time just on the water.
I&amp;rsquo;m still not thrilled with how the splash looks, but it looks better than it did. I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it and if it still bothers me in a year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep working on it. For now, IT&amp;rsquo;S FINE.
&amp;hellip;Same goes for a lot of these pages.
Rework Plan continued Quick update on where I&amp;rsquo;m at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colored Pages 2, 3, 4, and 8 (Book 1)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:25:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</guid>
      <description>Settlers-scene all done!
I decided to get all the pages in this scene out of the way. This scene only ranges from 2 through 8 (seven pages). I feel less cringy about these &amp;ldquo;flashback&amp;rdquo; pages now that they&amp;rsquo;re colored and the text boxes look cleaner.
The featured images above are the parts of the pages I like the most, but I sense, as I look back over the pages, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming back to touch up the coloring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 7 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</guid>
      <description>Wolf! I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with this redone page! I was originally just going to fill in the existing line work digitally, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too sure with the result, so I redrew Wolf. It looks SO much better!
The following changes were made to page 7:  Redrew panel 1 (kept the same glow lines). Colored whole page. Redrew text boxes and updated text box fonts. Updated sound effect in panel 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</guid>
      <description>Back to the chase! The only part of this page that needed fixing was the very last panel. I had no problem with how I drew Errie tripping over a tree stump, but the lines in her jeans coincided with the lines in the panel above.
One of the tips I learned from an artist I follow online is that it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid what he called &amp;ldquo;tangent lines&amp;rdquo; between panels, so that the lines don&amp;rsquo;t stop a person&amp;rsquo;s eyes from moving around the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</guid>
      <description>Definitely needed to revise this page I remember when I was finalizing the character design for Nascha. I felt so certain about the hair style I gave her. Now, 2 years later, I look at this page and think that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like time to curb one&amp;rsquo;s style choices.
So I changed Nascha&amp;rsquo;s hair. I like how her bangs frame her face.
An important rule for text in comics The most jarring feature of this page were the walls of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 14 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 09:09:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</guid>
      <description>SPEECH BUBBLES Changes on this page mostly consist of reformatting the characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue! A few changes were made to what was said, but none were of great consequence. They were a result of trying to make the conversation and speech bubbles make better sense.
Speaking of, I learned a lot about how to make clearer speech bubbles from a resource that one of my brothers shared with me. It has a lot of great tips in it about creating dialogue in comics, many of which about issues I did not foresee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 6 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:46:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</guid>
      <description>YUS. I really like how this page turned out! I&amp;rsquo;m super proud of the newly-inked Wolf and the colors.
Color Balance This is the first page I tried out the color balance tool to adjust the colors. Basically, I fill in the areas with the true colors, but then adjust them so that they look more like they would at a sunrise. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with the results.
Now I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go back to page 5 to adjust the colors accordingly&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 28 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:30:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</guid>
      <description>Happy Vines Ode to Bob Ross:
This week&amp;rsquo;s reworked page features a variety of happy vines&amp;hellip;a short, stumpy vine here&amp;hellip;a long, slender vine there&amp;hellip;a beautiful scenery filled with happy vines.
This week&amp;rsquo;s updated page is page 28 (Book 1)!
What changed on page 28 I think drawing all the vines in Book 1 had to be the most challenging part of the whole book. Part of it is b/c they&amp;rsquo;re so elaborate and I spend a lot of time on them, but also the fact that they had to be glowing most of the time and I draw all the glows in ink first&amp;hellip;It got a little over-the-top on some pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 23 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:58:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! Page 23 of Book 1 is updated! The fourth panel is featured above.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to redraw much on this page. The most change is probably the facial expressions in the second and fourth panels. Just redoing those was a vast improvement for the whole page.
I also adjusted the drawing of Errie in the second panel. I literally just panned it downwards to make more space in the panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 10 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 12:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome Back! I hope you all had a great holiday season! Thanks to the month off from posting pages, I got more time and energy to focus on spending time with family and had a great time.
Now that my break is over, I definitely feel more creative energy to work with&amp;hellip; but not in the way I expected.
Trial Run I was feeling really motivated to color a Book 1 page last week, so I decided to jump on page 10&amp;ndash;which is uploaded today, btw&amp;ndash;since it was mostly finished anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2018</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 21:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve joked about them, I guess those antlers are sticking around&amp;hellip; But what can I say? They make Christmas posts fun!
Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays! I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my break so far. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to do only one post for the holidays. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stack up too many tasks for myself and be so focused on the amount of workload ahead of me. Only needing to finish this one update made drawing it very fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 32</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 13:49:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</guid>
      <description>YAY I DID IT!
This one took me a while! Can you tell??? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t talk myself out of having to draw the water, it was required by the plotline.
But at least now one of Tenti&amp;rsquo;s abilities is pretty obvious&amp;hellip;and hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s obvious what&amp;rsquo;s NOT her ability. No &amp;ldquo;FSSHH&amp;rdquo; sounds while she&amp;rsquo;s running is a dead giveaway.
Well, time for a break. Here&amp;rsquo;s the plan. I still have a lot of pages ahead of me to complete Book 2, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking as good of a break as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-10-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 11:45:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m extending the delay on page 32. I got as far as adding true colors, but I still have the text with text bubbles and shading left to do.
I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing out about it though, because now&amp;rsquo;s a good time for&amp;hellip;
Morphic Character Feature! Today&amp;rsquo;s post features a brief history on that scary, purple-glowing lady in my timeline of writing &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;!
I thought about keeping her name secret until it was actually mentioned in the comic, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see any significant repercussions in sharing it, so WHAT THE HEY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-03-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:14:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</guid>
      <description>Ballpoint pen drawings of Errie and Vix
No page today&amp;mdash;Hope you like sticky notes As expected, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time this week to work on page 32. Even before posting the previous page, I felt more confident about getting it done this coming week, what with Halloween and All Saint&amp;rsquo;s Day among other things to worry about.
Nevertheless, I still have a lot to get done on page 32 in one week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 31</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 17:18:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-31/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for the really late update!
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot to balance this week, including how to proceed as far as uploading pages goes. I thought long an hard on this particular topic and I came to a decision. After I upload page 32, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin my break from drawing pages, to be resumed the beginning of January.
My main two reasons for choosing to take a break early consist of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (10-20-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 11:48:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-10-20-2018/</guid>
      <description>No page update today. Still working on page 31. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough week, but as I mentioned in a previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing a bit of drawing fatigue. I think I exhausted my creative energy and that&amp;rsquo;s not surprising considering that I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing AND coloring 30 pages since March, keeping a weekly upload schedule, AND on top of that doing some extra posts for celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 30</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 20:05:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-30/</guid>
      <description>So excited right now.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a LONG time to draw this lady. I&amp;rsquo;m even more excited about showing next week&amp;rsquo;s page!
Thanks for reading! Come back next week for another look at the new character! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 29</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 11:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-29/</guid>
      <description>Errie is ready to go!
Also, that stone&amp;hellip;I tend to forget about it!
It&amp;rsquo;s like one of those little details that you know is important but its ability to keep your interest wanes after a while&amp;hellip; Like in Book 1, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember to show Errie putting it in her pocket. She basically picked it up and forgot all about it and I totally forgot about it until planning for Errie to find it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 28</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 09:29:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-28/</guid>
      <description>It took almost 30 pages for Errie to realize something&amp;rsquo;s wrong.
But the pace picks up yet again!
Building up a Buffer I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on the next two pages. Although I fully expect to have next week&amp;rsquo;s page done in time to upload, I made a goal to build up my buffer of pages again.
Holidays are coming up and I want to try drawing up enough pages to give me a few weeks&amp;rsquo; break from drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:54:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-4/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 4 of my drawing process! We are now at the final post dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out page 27! Just click the link to go back a page to see it.
Part 4: Color Stage Last week, I talked about using GIMP to turn my pages from image files to layered lines and text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 27</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 22:52:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-27/</guid>
      <description>So while finalizing the script on this page, a familiar song came to mind: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a Believer&amp;rdquo;, written by Neil Diamond and sung by the Monkees. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop laughing.
Also, NEW CHARACTER APPEARANCE! This will be fun&amp;hellip; [hehehe]
Sorry for late update I&amp;rsquo;ve been crazy busy lately. Starting this week, I&amp;rsquo;ll be resuming a 2-page-per-week production schedule to build my page buffer up again. My goal is to get enough pages stored up to cover more than a month of weekly page updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-3/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 3 of my drawing process! We are now at the third of four posts dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. Don’t forget to check out page 26! Just click the left arrow icon to go back a page and see it.
Part 3: Text Stage Here’s where the drawing process starts to get techy. I use a program called GIMP for adding text and color layers to my pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 26</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 20:35:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-26/</guid>
      <description>Catius is really proud of his skillz.
Check out this week&amp;rsquo;s extra post! Part 3 of &amp;ldquo;How I Draw&amp;rdquo; is up!
2 years ago, I only got to this stage in page production. Believe me, it&amp;rsquo;s a relief to finally get to color these pages. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about my progress on coloring pages next week, but I hope you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying this glimpse into my drawing process.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing this comic for two years between college semesters, summer classes, and a part-time job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:24:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-2/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Welcome to Part 2 of my drawing process!
We are now at the second of four posts dedicated to showing how I create the pages of “Morphic”. But don’t worry&amp;ndash;page 25 is also posted! Just click the left navigation button to see it.
Part 2: Ink Stage Out of all four stages, this one is definitely the shortest. It often takes me under an hour to ink one page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 25</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-25/</guid>
      <description>YAY FOR CATZZZZZZZZZ
Keeping this brief: I have ONE PAGE in my buffer! Boy, am I getting places&amp;hellip;
And continuing with celebrating &amp;lsquo;Morphic&amp;rsquo;s birthday&amp;hellip;
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out this week&amp;rsquo;s SPECIAL POST: How I Draw, Part 2
Thanks for reading! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Draw, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/how-i-draw-part-1/</guid>
      <description>How I Make a Page Have you ever wondered how digital art is made? Many styles exist, as do many methods. To celebrate two years of drawing “Morphic”, I’m happy to share a glimpse into my drawing process. I have a lot to say about each stage, so I’ll be dedicating four separate posts to cover how I make a page, one post for each stage. Regular page updates are still going and you can check them out by pressing the back/forward icons or clicking a recent post link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 24</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:07:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-24/</guid>
      <description>Behold&amp;hellip;CAT MORPHICS
MEOW
&amp;hellip;also, cats are kind of hard to draw&amp;hellip;
Happy Birthday, Morphic! About two years ago, I launched &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; and posted the first 8 pages of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; Book 1 on a Facebook page. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact date, but I remember drawing these first pages in August, hurrying to get them done by the end of the month, then posting them on the first weekend of September. So I consider Sept 1st to be the birthday of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 23</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 22:38:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-23/</guid>
      <description>OUT INTO THE SUN AT LAST!
I got two more pages drawn and inked this week&amp;mdash;YAY! I expect to have those done by the end of next week.
Colored Page 15 is up! Check out page 15 of Book 1 to see the new changes!
Also, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this is a local server issue when I &amp;lsquo;test run&amp;rsquo; the post, but in case it is also an issue with the public-side of the website&amp;hellip;well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 22</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:21:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-22/</guid>
      <description>DUN DUN DUN
Aaaaaaand scene. I&amp;rsquo;m letting the suspense sit for a while. In the meantime, we&amp;rsquo;re going check out what the other characters are up to&amp;hellip;
Yet another busy week! You guessed it, no new colored pages in Book 1 this week. I am even busier than last week, it seems. Lots of new stuff coming up and limited access to wifi didn&amp;rsquo;t help. Thankfully, this page buffer helps me to not worry about new pages for Book 2, since I still have new pages ready for the next two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 21</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 09:43:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-21/</guid>
      <description>YYYYYYYYYYYYYYYYeah. Something&amp;rsquo;s up.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week I got two more pages colored like I expected to, so my page buffer is now up to 3 pages, as predicted. However, that was all I was I able to finish this week.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have another Book 1 page ready to update, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have better luck next week.
Until then&amp;hellip;
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to see the last page of this scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 20</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 20:38:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-20/</guid>
      <description>WELL UH OH
Things are about to get interesting&amp;hellip;again.
Taking it easy I decided to take a break from drawing last week, so now as of today, my buffer consists of only two pages. OH WELL.
Good news is, I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of coloring 2 more pages, so I anticipate having a 3-page buffer after next week&amp;rsquo;s update.
Another colored page in Book 1 Check out page 27 ! It&amp;rsquo;s fun to see how the glowing vines turn out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 19</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 11:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-19/</guid>
      <description>Dancing around the question. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so many investigation dramas, but making one is pretty fun.
Another Colored Page Check out page 16 of Book 1!
If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering how I&amp;rsquo;m choosing which pages to work on, basically I&amp;rsquo;m starting out with the pages that need the most alteration. Thus, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot of pages at the beginning of Book 1 refinished first before those in the last half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 18</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 07:47:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-18/</guid>
      <description>The sheriff makes another appearance.
He&amp;rsquo;s probably curious about some word changes I just made on some pages. I replaced &amp;lsquo;heatstroke&amp;rsquo; with &amp;lsquo;dehydration&amp;rsquo; on pages 14 and 16 of Book 2. See, I didn&amp;rsquo;t read up on what heatstroke was until I uploaded the page. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say it implies more of a life- and-death situation than I&amp;rsquo;d like (think &amp;lsquo;coma&amp;rsquo;&amp;mdash;I slap myself for not looking harder at the &amp;lsquo;stroke&amp;rsquo; side of &amp;lsquo;heatstroke&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 17</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 18:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-17/</guid>
      <description>Ooooooooooooooooooooooooo
Something&amp;rsquo;s clearly up. Who listens to the radio while switching loads?
{cough} {cough} SARCASM {cough}
Anyway long time no see, Lane One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked about drawing Lane is how easy her hairstyle is to draw. Or at least it feels that way. I never had to use a photo reference for it.
In contrast, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that having references for drawing Errie and her mother&amp;rsquo;s hair more realistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 16</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 11:31:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-16/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, Chan looks surprised.
End of scene Hope you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying the story so far! Come back next week to see the start of the next scene. We&amp;rsquo;ll get to see what Lane is up to.
Page 9 of Book 1 is now in color! Check it out here!
Thanks for reading! And have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 15</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:46:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-15/</guid>
      <description>The Burning Question Errie&amp;rsquo;s a little surprised to be regaining her mother&amp;rsquo;s trust so quickly.
A Small update Before last week, I was producing two colored pages per week for Book 2, with the intent of reaching a buffer of 8 pages. Since last week, I decided to slow down to producing one page per week, settling for a buffer of 5 pages.
&amp;hellip;Or, rather 3 pages currently. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the two latest pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 14</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:08:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-14/</guid>
      <description>Well darn&amp;hellip; Aw, heck. Who needs emergency services anyway?
 Also&amp;hellip;
SURPRISE! I said last week that I might have a redrawn and colored page for Book 1. I am happy to announce&amp;hellip; I have two!
Check out pages 1 and 37!
Thanks for reading! Check out next week&amp;rsquo;s page update to find out what happens and maybe&amp;mdash;maybe&amp;mdash;you&amp;rsquo;ll get to see another redone page from Book 1! Have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 13</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 16:51:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-13/</guid>
      <description>HUH&amp;hellip; Nothing like a see-through, walk-through tiger in the kitchen to make one question her own senses.
Quick Status! Book 2 page buffer is still growing. Yay!
I decided to redraw and color one of the Book 1 pages and now that it&amp;rsquo;s done, it&amp;rsquo;s uploaded! Check out page 5!
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to see the next page of book 2! And who knows, there could be another colored/updated page of book 1&amp;hellip;maybe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 12</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 10:45:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-12/</guid>
      <description>Yeah Mom, get off the phone Smartphones are so distracting, you know? It keeps people from noticing things going on around them, including the important stuff&amp;hellip;such as when there&amp;rsquo;s a tiger in the kitchen.
Status Update I&amp;rsquo;m making good progress on growing my page buffer. So far I&amp;rsquo;m finished with pages up to page 16, which covers about a month of weekly updates (yay!). I&amp;rsquo;m also starting to chip away at the rework of some of the pages for Book 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 11</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:04:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-11/</guid>
      <description>WHOA Errie, was that your stomach growling?
It&amp;rsquo;s times like this, when I really look forward to drawing Book 2&amp;hellip;
[Sinister chuckling]
Come back next week to find out what&amp;rsquo;s in the kitchen! Thanks for reading! And have a great weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 10</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-10/</guid>
      <description>The fox is in I like how Errie&amp;rsquo;s mom came out in panel 5. Really shows her protective side.
I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of coloring the next two pages, so I plan on uploading page 11 next week as planned.
Thanks for reading! Come back next week to find out what happens on the next page. Have a good Memorial Day weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 9</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 08:14:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-09/</guid>
      <description>Doodling Capri is the best.
Early Update I&amp;rsquo;m going out of town this week, so I&amp;rsquo;m posting this page today. I finished page 10 as expected, so I have no worries about posting it on time next week. Yay for meeting deadlines!
Anyways, now we get more of an explanation about the jar referenced in the last page of Book 1.
Thanks for reading! Next week&amp;rsquo;s page will have a change in pace, so remember to come back and check out what happens!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 8</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 23:51:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-08/</guid>
      <description>Definitely proud of this page&amp;mdash;especially the last panel.
All done! School is officially over for me and I got to draw a bunch this week. I just got page 9 done, so next week&amp;rsquo;s page is ready to upload. I&amp;rsquo;m also nearly done with page 10.
However, even though summer is here, I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much time on my hands because I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to working more. (It helps that I do not have classes, har har.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 7</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 07:50:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-07/</guid>
      <description>NICE TAIL CHAN So proud of his expression in panel 5.
Almost done with the semester! I&amp;rsquo;m itching to get done with my schoolwork so that I can get back into drawing more pages.
Also, in case you missed my unscheduled announcement earlier this week, you can now make comments on my posts through Disqus! As I understand it, you do have to create a free account with Disqus in order to comment, but it&amp;rsquo;s FREE and you can comment on any site that uses Disqus and that includes a lot of sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 6</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 22:03:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-06/</guid>
      <description>Where have we seen this guy before&amp;hellip;? Oh yeah&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s Chan! The kid who skipped out on going to the festival with his friends and thereby ended up missing out on an exciting (and slightly terrifying) adventure in the woods.
YEP. That&amp;rsquo;s him!
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you&amp;rsquo;ll be seeing a lot more of him in this book&amp;hellip; [cackles quietly and ominously]
In other news The next two pages actually took the most time to produce out of all my colored pages so far!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 5</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 18:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-05/</guid>
      <description>Gosh&amp;hellip;some days it feels like I go overboard on these inks, but talk about shading a darkened room!
However, I do really like how the color-shading pops out in this page.
Status Update: Buffer Complete! Every weekly update from now until the end of finals week is finished and ready to upload. As I wrap up this semester I&amp;rsquo;ll upload these posts, but I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on drawing more pages until I&amp;rsquo;m close to done with school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 17:23:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-04/</guid>
      <description>And now back to our protagonist!
I&amp;rsquo;m going to miss drawing these landscapes. They were super easy and very pretty!
Short Update I didn&amp;rsquo;t stick with the daily posts of fox videos this week. I got really busy and I kept forgetting.
However, based on previous experience, I never really got much reaction on those video posts. Therefore, I think I should just stick to posting a few videos every now and then, instead of a whole week of daily posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 23:29:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-03/</guid>
      <description>A great reminder to not run drowsy&amp;hellip;especially if you run fast.
Guess what I forgot last week Remember that last week we saw Vix transform? Remember what I usually do when we see a Morphic transform for the first time in the story? That&amp;rsquo;s right&amp;mdash;It&amp;rsquo;s video-sharing time! Featuring foxes!
Without further ado&amp;hellip;
WHAT DOES THE FOX SAY
Thanks for reading! I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting more fox videos on my Facebook page throughout the week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 22:12:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-02/</guid>
      <description>Hmmm&amp;hellip;where have we seen that wolf before&amp;hellip;?
And oh yeah, now we know the Fox is a she.
Short Post I&amp;rsquo;m a little busy this weekend, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just give a quick status update. I have pages finished up to page 6 now&amp;mdash;WOW. I was on fire this week with pages 5 and 6. If I can manage to get the next two done next week, I&amp;rsquo;m set for the rest of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 22:01:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-01/</guid>
      <description>First colored Morphic page ever! Welcome back from the intermission! Hope you like the new character and the new coloring style.
I managed to finish coloring page 2 and now I&amp;rsquo;m coloring pages 3 and 4 (got all the other drawing for those pages done and only the coloring is left).
I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with my progress so far, but now Spring Break is over and I have to buckle down for the second half of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 8</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:56:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-08/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 9/24/16. Colored in GIMP and updated 3/2/19.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 7</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:55:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 9/17/16. Colored with GIMP and updated 2/23/19.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 6</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:54:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 9/10/16. Colored in GIMP and updated on 1/25/19.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 5</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:53:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-05/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 9/3/16. Colored and reworked in GIMP. Updated 6/15/18.
Updated again 2/2/19. Shifted color balance and color of lighting.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:52:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-04/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 8/27/16. Colored in GIMP and updated 3/2/19.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-03/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 8/27/16. Colored in GIMP and updated 3/2/19.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:50:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02-old/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 8/27/16. Colored in GIMP and updated 3/2/19.
Replaced with new page on 5/8/20. See the new page.
Moved from Book 1 to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Prologue, Page 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-01-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:49:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-01-old/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted 8/27/16. Replaced with new page 6/23/2018. See the new page.
Added to Misc on 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #5</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 23:40:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_5/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s one wishlist item checked off my list: Lane jamming out to tunes on her headphones.
Good news! I started drawing pages for Book 2.
I would have liked to finish writing Book 3 before drawing, but I decided to take the plunge and come back to it. What&amp;rsquo;s nice about graphic novels is that I can go back and forth between writing and drawing when I need to.
As of writing this post, I completed the flatting stage for pages 1 and 2 of Book 1 and started the actual coloring and shading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #4</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 20:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Wolf Will you look at that&amp;mdash;It&amp;rsquo;s COLOR!
Usually I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have time to complete the coloring for a picture, but I got this portrait done in less than two days, including the coloring. This fact alone suggests two things:
 I&amp;rsquo;m finally figuring out how I like my coloring, and I have the ability to color in a short amount of time after all.  However, this portrait is a very simple one with a minimal color palette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #3</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/capri-art-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 07:42:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/capri-art-update/</guid>
      <description>The main antagonist of Book 1. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to drawing a portrait of Capri and his vines for some time.
Extending Break By Two Weeks I&amp;rsquo;m still in the process of rewriting the series. I got really busy the past couple of weeks and I had enough time for intermission art and launching a website (and cleaning up the bugs following launch).
Not to worry though! That&amp;rsquo;s an excuse enough for me to draw more character portraits anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 19:07:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/intermission_art_2/</guid>
      <description>New Site Launched! I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of myself for getting this site done!
 I uploaded all the pages for Book 1, plus the latest art updates. You can navigate to any part of the plot easily!  &amp;lsquo;Recent Posts&amp;rsquo; on the side bar shows latest content. &amp;lsquo;Blog&amp;rsquo; on the navigation menu displays posts from earliest to latest. Plus I included navigation to previous/next posts at the top and bottom of each post!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:55:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/wolf/</guid>
      <description>This mysterious Morphic appears to early settlers and, over a century later, reappears near Lane&amp;rsquo;s house where Errie found the stone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/sirena/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:40:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/sirena/</guid>
      <description>Despite her cold, critical attitude, Sirena jumps into action to save the humans of Ash Root from the urgent threat of a nearby Rogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/canissandro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:38:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/canissandro/</guid>
      <description>In addition to his loyalty and tender heart, Canissandro seeks boldly to make up for his mistakes&amp;ndash;especially that which brought Capri to Ash Root.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/capri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:37:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/capri/</guid>
      <description>A stubborn Goat Morphic with a chip on his shoulder, Capri angrily denies Errie and Lane&amp;rsquo;s observation of the unnatural plant growth protruding from his back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/nascha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:10:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/nascha/</guid>
      <description>As suddenly as she appears to plead for Errie&amp;rsquo;s help, this mysterious girl vanishes into thin air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/chan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:56:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/chan/</guid>
      <description>Chan&amp;rsquo;s dedication to building the &amp;ldquo;best remote-control car ever&amp;rdquo; prevents him from joining his friends Errie and Lane on their adventures in the woods, but he accepts the costume they got him to wear at the festival later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:37:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/lane/</guid>
      <description>As Errie&amp;rsquo;s best friend with a concern for others&amp;rsquo; safety, Lane wastes no time to check out Errie&amp;rsquo;s alert about someone in danger in the woods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/errie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 13:37:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/characters/errie/</guid>
      <description>While Errie waits to attend a local festival, an unnamed girl seeks her help in the woods and there Errie meets a Rogue Morphic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermission Art #1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/errie-art-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:05:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/errie-art-update/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 74</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-74/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 73</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-73/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 72</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-72/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 71</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-71/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 70</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 17:21:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-70/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 69</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 17:20:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-69/</guid>
      <description>Updated 7/13/18 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 68</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-68/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 67</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-67/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2017</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 17:30:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 66</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-66/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-66/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 65</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-65/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 64</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-64/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 63</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-63/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-63/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 62</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-62/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 61</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-61/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 5/4/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 60</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-60/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 4/20/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 59</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-59/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 58</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-58/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 57</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-57/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 56</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-56/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 55</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-55/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 54</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-54/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 53</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-53/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 52</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-52/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 51</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-51/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 50</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-50/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 49</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-49/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 48</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-48/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 47</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-47/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 4/27/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 46</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-46/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 45</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-45/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 44</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-44/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 43</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-43/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 42</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-42/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 5/18/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 41</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-41/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 5/11/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 40</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-40/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 39</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-39/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 38</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-38/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 4/13/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 37</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-37/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 36</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-36/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and uploaded on 4/6/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 35</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-35/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and uploaded on 3/30/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 34</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-34/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 33</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-33/</guid>
      <description>Colored with GIMP and updated on 3/23/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 32</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-32/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 3/16/19 11/30/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 31</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-31/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19
Updated 2/29/20, with sound effects added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 30</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 3/8/19 11/30/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29/</guid>
      <description>Colored with GIMP. Updated 2/16/19.
Updated 2/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 28</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28/</guid>
      <description>Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 1/19/19.
Updated 2/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 27</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-27/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 8/3/18.
Re-uploaded with new text for sound effects 1/19/19.
Updated 2/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 26</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-26/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 2/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 25</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-25/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 2/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 24</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-24/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 23</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23/</guid>
      <description>Colored and reworked with GIMP and uploaded on 1/11/18 11/30/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 16:22:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22/</guid>
      <description>Colored with GIMP. Updated and uploaded on 2/9/19 11/30/19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 21</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 16:21:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-21/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 20</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 16:19:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-20/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 19</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-19/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2016</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 18</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-18/</guid>
      <description>Updated 11/30/19
Made panel line thicker between last two panels &amp;ndash; 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 17</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-17/</guid>
      <description>Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 16</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-16/</guid>
      <description>Updated 7/28/18
Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 15</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-15/</guid>
      <description>Updated 8/24/18
Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 14</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14/</guid>
      <description>Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 13</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-13/</guid>
      <description>Colored and reworked with GIMP. Updated 8/29/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 12</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-12/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 7/21/18.
Updated 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 11</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-11/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and updated 7/13/18.
Updated 5/8/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 10</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10/</guid>
      <description>Colored with GIMP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 9</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-09/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 2</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 17:46:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02/</guid>
      <description>Colored in GIMP and replaced original page on 5/8/20. See original page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 1</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-01/</guid>
      <description>Colored with GIMP and replaced original page on 6/23/2018. See original page.
Updated 5/9/20.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>