<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morphic Graphic Novel Series</title>
    <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Morphic Graphic Novel Series</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Morphic</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/about</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-author&#34;&gt;The Author&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My name is Maria Rice&lt;/strong&gt; and I am a web developer by trade
with a passion for reading web comics, graphic novels, comic
books, etc. &lt;strong&gt;And I enjoy comics so much that I make one of
my very own!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-plot&#34;&gt;The Plot&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Erica &amp;ldquo;Errie&amp;rdquo; Bright, a regular teenaged girl who
discovers the existence of powerful beings called Morphics
just outside her hometown of Ash Root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-morphics&#34;&gt;What are &amp;lsquo;Morphics&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerful beings with the ability to switch between either of
two forms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That of an animal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That which is similar to a human, but with some animal
features corresponding to their animal form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Morphic can have more abilities in addition to his/her
transformation ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the first finished plot line for &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; in the
spring of 2016. I posted the first drawn pages in September
of that same year and have been uploading pages weekly ever
since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; was going to be a 5-book series, but after
discovering how much time and effort it takes to produce
one book, I changed it to a 3-book series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;medium&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I hope to gradually add color to the pages as the
project grows, for now I show it in the original black and
white to keep the story going. I draw the pages with black
ink pen and add the speech bubbles with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-visiting&#34;&gt;Thanks For Visiting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With immense gratitude, I welcome you to view my work and
leave some constructive feedback. I hope you enjoy the story
as much as I enjoy creating it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 30 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 18:10:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;splash&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splash!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was a &lt;strong&gt;doozy!&lt;/strong&gt; I spent a long time just on the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not thrilled with how the splash looks, but it looks better than it did. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it and if it still bothers me in a year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep working on it. For now, IT&amp;rsquo;S FINE.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Same goes for a lot of these pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rework-plan-continued&#34;&gt;Rework Plan continued&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick update on where I&amp;rsquo;m at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; pages reworked and colored (not all uploaded)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; pages left to color (two of them call for rework)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So out of 74 pages in Book 1, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;43%&lt;/strong&gt; of the way done&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;almost half-way!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that most of the finished pages needed the most work, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m optimistic about getting the rest of the pages done in less time&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt; but I still hold reservations about whether I&amp;rsquo;ll stay motivated to keep going with Book 1 pages before transitioning back into Book 2. Of course, the only way I&amp;rsquo;ll know is by trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-term goal: get enough pages done for &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; more weekly updates!&lt;/strong&gt; I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how many pages I have ready to upload, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough to cover all but 3 weeks before June (my break month).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I say 3 weekly updates, I don&amp;rsquo;t just mean single page updates&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;some weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll upload &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; pages!&lt;/strong&gt; Like &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only doing that b/c I&amp;rsquo;m so far ahead on these reworked pages.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to feature a before-and-after comparison of color-only pages, as the changes won&amp;rsquo;t be as drastic. In addition, these color-only pages should proceed fast enough to upload them in batches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I&amp;rsquo;ll take my month-long break and I&amp;rsquo;ll decide how to proceed with my update schedule when I return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-30/&#34;&gt;page 30&lt;/a&gt;, fully-colored. And come back next week to see another reworked page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colored Pages 2, 3, 4, and 8 (Book 1)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:25:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/colored-pages-02-03-04-and-08-book-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlers-scene all done!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to get all the pages in this scene out of the way. This scene only ranges from 2 through 8 (seven pages). &lt;strong&gt;I feel less cringy about these &amp;ldquo;flashback&amp;rdquo; pages now that they&amp;rsquo;re colored &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the text boxes look cleaner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The featured images above are the parts of the pages I like the most, but I sense, as I look back over the pages, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be coming back to touch up the coloring. No doubt the pages look better with color, but I see parts that could use a little polish. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; rushing a little when I did these. &lt;strong&gt;Pretty backgrounds require a bit of patience, you know?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;behind-the-scenes-update&#34;&gt;Behind the scenes update&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, so I said I would post colored Book 1 pages until the first post in March and then announce further news about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing behind the scenes. So here&amp;rsquo;s the update&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-book-2&#34;&gt;About Book 2&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing some writer&amp;rsquo;s block.&lt;/strong&gt; I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten much further with the current pages that are in progress (35 and 36). It&amp;rsquo;s clear from my work on all these Book 1 pages (some of which required redrawing some areas) that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem of wanting to draw at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon further reflection, it dawned on me that my primary motivation for drawing all these pages was my excitement for an upcoming scene in the story. &lt;strong&gt;So if I can reignite my excitement for the ending of Book 2, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to finish these current pages and continue the story!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; excited right now?! Good question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m just dreading having to make final decisions about the plot. I like to create lots of loose ends and I get anxious about tying them up just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never experienced this kind of writer&amp;rsquo;s block for Book 1 and it didn&amp;rsquo;t dawn on me until recently why that is. &lt;strong&gt;With Book 1, I drew out ALL the possible scenes in sequential order.&lt;/strong&gt; I ended up drawing thumbnails for&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;130 pages?&lt;/em&gt; This was before I shortened the storyline to 74 pages, but it helped me figure out how I wanted the story to go. I could visualize all the scenes I wanted and how/why they came about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Book 2, I skipped drawing out the whole story line, b/c I was already sure of how it would start.&lt;/strong&gt; I just wanted to dive in and figure out the rest of the plot as I went along. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m approaching the last scene I&amp;rsquo;m more certain about, I feel anxious about the &amp;ldquo;gray areas&amp;rdquo; coming up that I need to decide on and when I get anxious, I tend to freeze up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SO THERE. I need to draw out the scenes of Book 2.&lt;/strong&gt; I actually started doing that and it&amp;rsquo;s going very well! My goal is to get to the end of Book 2 with a more detailed idea of the sequence of events. Then some scene that I draw roughly will get me &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; excited to continue drawing pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-meantime&#34;&gt;In the meantime&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep coloring Book 1 pages! I already have a third of the pages done (maybe not uploaded yet) and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the momentum going away. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just plan on continuing posting colored pages through the end of May, after which I&amp;rsquo;ll take a month-long break.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll keep figuring out the story of Book 2 and hope that I can continue the story after that break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out pages &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-02/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-03/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-04/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-08/&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;! Next week will just be a single page, but a lot has changed on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 7 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 08:51:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wolf&#34;&gt;Wolf!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with this redone page! I was originally just going to fill in the existing line work digitally, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too sure with the result, so I redrew Wolf. It looks &lt;em&gt;SO&lt;/em&gt; much better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-following-changes-were-made-to-page-7&#34;&gt;The following changes were made to page 7:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew panel 1 (kept the same glow lines).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colored whole page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redrew text boxes and updated text box fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated sound effect in panel 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the new page 7 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-07/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;Next week, I look forward to doing something a little different than the usual,&lt;/strong&gt; so don&amp;rsquo;t forget to come back and check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 29 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 08:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-the-chase&#34;&gt;Back to the chase!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only part of this page that needed fixing was the very last panel.&lt;/strong&gt; I had no problem with how I drew Errie tripping over a tree stump, but the lines in her jeans coincided with the lines in the panel above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the tips I learned from an artist I follow online is that &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid what he called &amp;ldquo;tangent lines&amp;rdquo; between panels, so that the lines don&amp;rsquo;t stop a person&amp;rsquo;s eyes from moving around the page.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure enough, the more I looked at this page, the more my eyes stopped at that intersection above this panel. &lt;strong&gt;So I endeavored to modify it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-one-thing-leads-to-another&#34;&gt;But one thing leads to another&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my best to work with the existing linework and save the panel. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But alas!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing I tried sat right with me, so I resorted to redrawing the whole panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid finicking too long on the details, I opted for a silhouette in this panel. Now, after coloring the page, I have no regrets. &lt;strong&gt;It looks awesome!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed tangent lines before, but never with a complete redrawing. &lt;strong&gt;It usually only takes small modification&lt;/strong&gt;, but so much is happening on this page that proved challenging in all my attempts to fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh well&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out all of page 29 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-29/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I&amp;rsquo;ll feature one of the first ten pages of Book 1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; And have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 22 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:01:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;definitely-needed-to-revise-this-page&#34;&gt;Definitely needed to revise this page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was finalizing the character design for Nascha. I felt so certain about the hair style
I gave her. &lt;strong&gt;Now, 2 years later, I look at this page and think that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;
to curb one&amp;rsquo;s style choices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I changed Nascha&amp;rsquo;s hair. I like how her bangs frame her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-important-rule-for-text-in-comics&#34;&gt;An important rule for text in comics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most jarring feature of this page were the walls of text.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel less bad about this cringe-worthy
mistake, since it&amp;rsquo;s apparently a common one made by artists new to drawing comics.
And besides, the stuff that
Nascha says in those walls of text wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to convey any helpful information. It was meant to be
mysterious and not well understood by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That goal didn&amp;rsquo;t change since I drew this page, but after 2
years, I see the disadvantage of having all this text taking up whole panels:
&lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no clear direction to the reader on how to interpret what is going on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is someone talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is talking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do I start reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Reads it] &lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;Did I just waste five minutes reading redundant information?!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page makes more sense once Errie starts talking, but I knew it can do better. Therefore, I did away
with the walls of text and created new speech bubbles. &lt;strong&gt;Now, in addition to clarifying what Nascha is saying,
I&amp;rsquo;m introducing a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; mystery in the situation&amp;mdash;the presence of &lt;em&gt;two kinds&lt;/em&gt; of speech bubbles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it to the audience to figure out what this means, as the significance will be revealed by the
plot. In fact, you can find some hints in Book 2&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-22/&#34;&gt;Check out the rest of page 22!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll post another updated page, one that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; proud of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 14 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 09:09:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;speech-bubbles&#34;&gt;SPEECH BUBBLES&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes on this page mostly consist of reformatting the characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue! A &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; changes
were made to what was said, but none were of great consequence. They were a result of trying to
make the conversation and speech bubbles make better sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of, I learned a lot about how to make clearer speech bubbles from a resource that one
of my brothers shared with me. It has a lot of great tips in it about creating dialogue in comics,
many of which about issues I did not foresee. You can find this helpful resource &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blambot.com/articles_tips.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wellllllll&#34;&gt;wellllllll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have much more to say about this page. The only other change on this page (aside from coloring)
was redrawing Chan&amp;rsquo;s hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason I decided to work on this before the majority of pages was b/c the dialogue needed to look
right&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;and there is a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of dialogue on this page.&lt;/em&gt; So it got a high rework rating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; updated page has more lineart reworked on it, so the post for it next week will be a
lot more interesting!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-14/&#34;&gt;page 14 of Book 1&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week to see the next updated page. Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 6 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 19:46:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;yus&#34;&gt;YUS.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like how this page turned out! I&amp;rsquo;m super proud of the newly-inked Wolf and the colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;color-balance&#34;&gt;Color Balance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the first page I tried out the color balance tool to adjust the colors.&lt;/strong&gt; Basically, I fill
in the areas with the true colors, but then adjust them so that they look more like they would
at a sunrise. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with the results.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go back to page 5 to adjust the colors accordingly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;redrawing-wolf&#34;&gt;Redrawing Wolf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to redo panel 3. I found a good reference to use and redrew Wolf.
&lt;strong&gt;And oh my &lt;em&gt;goodness&lt;/em&gt; this panel is so &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;!!!&lt;/strong&gt; I put a lot of thought into it
and shrunk the guy down so that he&amp;rsquo;s looking &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; at the leaping Wolf. &lt;strong&gt;I always intended
this panel to be comical, but the eye contact between the characters is &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;
Redoing the guy&amp;rsquo;s expression also helped make the panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-glow-around-wolf&#34;&gt;Adding glow around Wolf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original page didn&amp;rsquo;t have any glows around Wolf, but I decided to add it in panel 3 for emphasis.
Therefore, I added the glow around Wolf in the other panels for consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-06/&#34;&gt;page 6&lt;/a&gt; of Book 1!
I&amp;rsquo;ll upload another updated page next week, &lt;strong&gt;so have a great weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1, Page 28 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:30:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;happy-vines&#34;&gt;Happy Vines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ode to Bob Ross:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s reworked page features a variety of happy vines&amp;hellip;a short, stumpy vine here&amp;hellip;a long, slender vine there&amp;hellip;a beautiful scenery&lt;/em&gt; filled &lt;em&gt;with happy vines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s updated page is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-28/&#34;&gt;page 28 (Book 1)&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-changed-on-page-28&#34;&gt;What changed on page 28&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think drawing all the vines in Book 1 had to be the most challenging part of the whole book.&lt;/strong&gt; Part of it
is b/c they&amp;rsquo;re so elaborate and I spend a lot of time on them, &lt;strong&gt;but also the fact that they had to be
&lt;em&gt;glowing&lt;/em&gt; most of the time&lt;/strong&gt; and I &lt;em&gt;draw&lt;/em&gt; all the glows in ink first&amp;hellip;It got a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; over-the-top on some
pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely happy that the reworking of the inks on this page &lt;strong&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t need any changes
on the vines&lt;/strong&gt;. I only modified Errie&amp;rsquo;s surprised expression on panel 2 and &lt;strong&gt;(the most dramatic change)&lt;/strong&gt;
I painstakingly &lt;strong&gt;erased&lt;/strong&gt; all the sound effects that where initially drawn in and recreated them digitally.
&lt;strong&gt;So all those &amp;lsquo;HHH&amp;rsquo;s you see&amp;hellip;they were in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; panel on both page 27 and 28. I erased &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t digging those hand-drawn words and how rough they looked. I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to get rid of them. &lt;strong&gt;So
I did.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore,&lt;/em&gt; in addition to uploading the new images for page 28, &lt;strong&gt;I also uploaded the updated image of page
27&lt;/strong&gt; so that both are consistent on how the sound effects are displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still other pages that have the hard-drawn sound effects, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to update those too when I
get to them. Ironically, I didn&amp;rsquo;t add &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lsquo;HHH&amp;rsquo;s on the following page (29)&amp;hellip;so &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; will be easy to
update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-assessment&#34;&gt;General Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This comic page is one of my more &lt;em&gt;exciting&lt;/em&gt; comic pages (before AND after coloring)&lt;/strong&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s
one of the first action scenes in Book 1 (probably #2, after the settlers&amp;rsquo; flashback). Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t
have to redo much of the inking on it either, I think it was also one of the strongest inked pages I&amp;rsquo;ve
made. The different character positions and angles I chose for all the panels did a good job of portraying
the back-and-forth movement of the character in flight defending herself from the pursuing vines. &lt;strong&gt;I am
especially proud of this action scene b/c it gives a further glimpse into Errie&amp;rsquo;s character&amp;mdash;her quick
response to a threat shows a rare display of resilience and boldness in this soft-spoken teenager.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think one of the reasons it was so well drawn was b/c I actually created a reference to draw
from. &lt;strong&gt;I recorded myself doing the exact swinging motion Errie is doing in the above featured panel&lt;/strong&gt; and
watched the video over and over to get the position just right. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great recording, so no individual
frame seemed suitable for what I wanted, but I got what I needed from the combined series of motions and
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WHA-LA&lt;/em&gt;! I made a panel that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; proud of!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on a roll this week coloring more pages! &lt;strong&gt;Next week will feature a page that &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; needed
TLC on the &lt;em&gt;inking&lt;/em&gt; side.&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks again for checking out what&amp;rsquo;s new on &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo; and have a great
weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 23 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:58:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-23/&#34;&gt;Page 23&lt;/a&gt; of Book 1 is updated!&lt;/strong&gt; The
fourth panel is featured above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to redraw much on this page. &lt;strong&gt;The most change is probably the facial expressions&lt;/strong&gt; in
the second and fourth panels. Just redoing those was a vast improvement for the whole page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also adjusted the drawing of Errie in the second panel. I literally just panned it downwards to make
more space in the panel. It was just&amp;hellip;too &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; to the fourth panel. I was thinking of redrawing it,
but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the drawing was too bad. Sometimes just looking at it and figuring out why it bothers
you helps with solving the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am finding this rework process &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; calming and therapeutic. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to coloring more pages
and sharing another one next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back next week for another colored page! Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 Page 10 REWORK</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 12:03:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10-rework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome Back!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all had a great holiday season! Thanks to the month off from posting pages,
I got more time and energy to focus on spending time with family and had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that my break is over, I definitely feel more creative energy to work with&amp;hellip;
&lt;em&gt;but not in the way I expected.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trial-run&#34;&gt;Trial Run&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was feeling really motivated to color a Book 1 page last week, so I decided to jump on
page 10&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book-1-page-10/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;which is uploaded today, btw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;since
it was &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; finished anyway. I ended up reworking the ink some more on it, but I finished it easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; week I started drawing pages 33 and 34&amp;hellip;and it took all I got just to finish the details
of &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I finished page 33, I sat back to look at both pages, one fully drawn and the other barely started.
I sat like this for probably 10 minutes, just to figure out what I was feeling. I came to the conclusion
that I&amp;rsquo;m still burnt out after my month-long break. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just not motivated to draw new pages right now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, it hit me that I&amp;rsquo;m actually excited about coloring Book 1 pages.&lt;/strong&gt; After drawing page 33, I felt
&lt;em&gt;motivated&lt;/em&gt; to color another Book 1 page and it&amp;rsquo;s nearly done as of writing this post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-reason-for-burnout&#34;&gt;Possible Reason for Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little stunned that I&amp;rsquo;m still not eager to continue Book 2 pages. I decided to look back at my upload
history around this time of the year for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what I found? &lt;strong&gt;I barely took any breaks.&lt;/strong&gt; And when I did, it was out of dire necessity to study
for finals week. That was basically it&amp;hellip; I didn&amp;rsquo;t take an intentional month-long break from updates since
&lt;em&gt;two years&lt;/em&gt; ago. &lt;strong&gt;No wonder I&amp;rsquo;m burnt out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;planning-for-this-year&#34;&gt;Planning for this year&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had in mind a month ago that I should plan on taking time off from drawing this year. &lt;strong&gt;I still think that I
should take a month off in June AND December&lt;/strong&gt;, just to see if it makes a difference in the work I produce.
That means only 10 months to draw, but last year I made only 32 new (fully-colored) pages and 10 reworked/colored
Book 1 pages. That means &lt;strong&gt;I produced 42 pages&lt;/strong&gt;, which is also roughly the &lt;strong&gt;same total number of pages I&amp;rsquo;d produce if I were only working 10 months&lt;/strong&gt; out of the year (10 months * 4 pages a month = 40 pages). &lt;strong&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; counting the miscellaneous posts, like the &amp;lsquo;How I Draw&amp;rsquo; posts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based off of these numbers and the results of my trial run, I think I have nothing to lose by planning for two months of break time this year. &lt;strong&gt;It may even help prevent burnout in years to come&amp;mdash;but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-for-weekly-updates&#34;&gt;As for weekly updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; motivated to keep coloring Book 1 pages, I&amp;rsquo;m going to upload &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; on a weekly basis&lt;/strong&gt;
and create miscellaneous posts to briefly compare/contrast the updated page and share the link to it.
It sucks that I can&amp;rsquo;t give new content right now, but there&amp;rsquo;s no getting around this&amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;page block&amp;rsquo;,
whatever this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep working on pages 33 and 34, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking my sweet time on those. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll
reassess my &amp;lsquo;creative state&amp;rsquo; again in March to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start on weekly page updates
for Book 2. &lt;strong&gt;Worst case scenario, I go through most of this year just coloring Book 1 pages&amp;mdash;really,
that&amp;rsquo;s not so bad.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do those anyway, but I was expecting to do them b/w Book 2 pages.
&lt;em&gt;Mrhh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least I can look forward to this year making Book 1 look like what it does in my head. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actually, I&lt;/em&gt; am
&lt;em&gt;looking forward to it&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-thoughts-until-next-week&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts until next week&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of when I continue Book 2, &lt;strong&gt;I still aim for 40 pages finished by the end of the year.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m
accepting any combination of reworked pages and new pages to reach this goal. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SO HERE GOES!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend and thanks for following! Feel free to like my Facebook page and reread the comic! See
you next week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas 2018</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 21:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/christmas-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;now-that-i-ve-joked-about-them-i-guess-those-antlers-are-sticking-around&#34;&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve joked about them, I guess those antlers are sticking around&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what can I say?&lt;/strong&gt; They make Christmas posts fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;merry-christmas-and-happy-holidays&#34;&gt;Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my break so far. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to do only one post for the holidays.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stack up too many tasks for myself and be so focused on the amount of workload
ahead of me. &lt;strong&gt;Only needing to finish this one update made drawing it &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you like this goofy Christmas art! I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of the Catz. Especially Catius and his
Chrismas lights&amp;hellip;and Tenti&amp;rsquo;s squid arms&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Well, gosh. I could go on and &lt;em&gt;on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-you-re-probably-wondering-about-the-next-update&#34;&gt;But you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering about the next update!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a deal with myself to &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; draw any pages until January. I want to enjoy this
holiday season &lt;em&gt;as much as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I also want to announce what my upload schedule will be like this coming year and I
still need time to think about it, so &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post a status update January 5th&lt;/strong&gt;. It won&amp;rsquo;t be
a &lt;em&gt;page&lt;/em&gt; update, but &lt;strong&gt;it will contain information on when I will post the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; page update
of the year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I&amp;rsquo;ll have&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;checks calendar&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;three weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to enjoy myself and strategize a little bit on what I&amp;rsquo;ll do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have some writing to do&amp;hellip;&lt;em&gt;and much staring at page-number stubs pinned to a bulletin board
on my wall and drumming my fingers together in deep concentration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aaaaaaaand I should get back to my break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have a wonderful holiday season! Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check for the next status update on January 5th.
&lt;strong&gt;Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2, Page 32</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 13:49:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/book2/book-2-page-32/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;YAY I DID IT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one took me a while! &lt;strong&gt;Can you tell???&lt;/strong&gt; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t talk myself out of
having to draw the water, &lt;em&gt;it was required by the plotline&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at least now one of Tenti&amp;rsquo;s abilities is pretty obvious&amp;hellip;and &lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt;
it&amp;rsquo;s obvious what&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; her ability. &lt;strong&gt;No &amp;ldquo;FSSHH&amp;rdquo; sounds while she&amp;rsquo;s running is a
dead giveaway.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;well-time-for-a-break-here-s-the-plan&#34;&gt;Well, time for a break. Here&amp;rsquo;s the plan.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a lot of pages ahead of me to complete Book 2, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking as
good of a break as I can. I say this b/c a month ago I was toying with the idea
of doing some extra &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; posts during my break. As cool as it sounded,
I knew I may lose motivation to keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m limiting myself to just uploading &lt;strong&gt;one single Christmas post&lt;/strong&gt;
and calling that good until the beginning of January. That way I can focus on
other things (like the holidays) and &lt;strong&gt;return to page production in January &lt;em&gt;refreshed and
full of energy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-sum-it-up&#34;&gt;To sum it up&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;drew&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;colored&lt;/strong&gt; 32 pages of Book 2 and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;colored&lt;/strong&gt; (and redrew) about 10 pages of Book 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am now starting my break from uploading pages and it will last through the
beginning of January&lt;/strong&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for the very beginning, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that
turns out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, &lt;strong&gt;I will plan on uploading one Christmas/holiday post&lt;/strong&gt; some
week prior to Christmas Day. I&amp;rsquo;ll aim for uploading this post on &lt;strong&gt;December 17th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy sharing my comic with you! Please like/comment on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/MorphicGraphicNovel&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;
Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, I like to see people&amp;rsquo;s feedback. I&amp;rsquo;ll be back on Dec. 17th with
the special Christmas post, so in the meantime, &lt;strong&gt;have a great weekend and a happy
Thanksgiving!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-10-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 11:45:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-10-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m extending the delay on page 32. I got as far as adding true colors, but I
still have the text with text bubbles and shading left to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing out about it though, because now&amp;rsquo;s a good time for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;morphic-character-feature&#34;&gt;Morphic Character Feature!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s post features a brief history on &lt;strong&gt;that scary, purple-glowing lady&lt;/strong&gt; in
my timeline of writing &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about keeping her name secret until it was actually mentioned in the
comic, but &lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see any significant repercussions in sharing it, so WHAT THE
HEY.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-tenti-the-squid&#34;&gt;Welcome Tenti the Squid!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with other Morphics, I followed the trend of naming her after the species I
based her off of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;species-and-name-inspiration&#34;&gt;Species and Name Inspiration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much research, I decided to base her off of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giant_squid&#34;&gt;Giant Squid, &lt;em&gt;Architeuthis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
The reason why I went with that specific kind of squid is because that&amp;rsquo;s the
&lt;strong&gt;largest&lt;/strong&gt; of all species of squid and &lt;strong&gt;it may have inspired stories of the
&lt;em&gt;Kraken&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s one of the more &lt;strong&gt;mysterious&lt;/strong&gt; species of squid, such that no one
could verify it&amp;rsquo;s existence except for their dead carcasses washing up on shore.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/edith_widder_how_we_found_the_giant_squid?language=en&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt;
all about some of the first video footage of a live Giant Squid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The species&amp;rsquo; name posed a problem for me in naming Tenti. I was thinking of &amp;lsquo;Toothy&amp;rsquo;
for a while (after &amp;lsquo;Archi&lt;strong&gt;tueth&lt;/strong&gt;is&amp;rsquo;), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. It didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to mesh
right with her character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I decided to name her after the number of tentacles a giant squid
has&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;. It also meshed well with &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;ten&lt;/strong&gt;tacles&amp;rsquo; and it sounded better than &amp;lsquo;Toothy&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, she&amp;rsquo;s always been very in&lt;strong&gt;ten&lt;/strong&gt;se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could keep going with this train of thought, but you get the idea. &lt;strong&gt;The name clicked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;clothing-and-appearance&#34;&gt;Clothing and Appearance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The images above are actual photos of sketches I drew of Tenti, dating from &lt;strong&gt;two years ago&lt;/strong&gt;,
(while writing the first finished script of &amp;ldquo;Morphic&amp;rdquo;) to &lt;strong&gt;earlier this year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within that timespan, she remained pretty consistent. I held to keeping her
dark-skinned and wearing attire similar to that worn in ancient northern Africa/Egypt.
I was attached to the idea of her wearing a dress at first, but this year &lt;strong&gt;I knew
I wanted to avoid drawing the folds of &lt;em&gt;that skirt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It also made sense to
make her look more like a mummy or dressed like a woman on a wall of an Egyptian
tomb. &lt;strong&gt;Therefore, the &lt;em&gt;really easy&lt;/em&gt; outfit that resulted&lt;/strong&gt; not only satisfied
these criteria, &lt;strong&gt;but also balanced out how hard it is to draw the rest of Tenti&amp;rsquo;s
appearance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, &lt;em&gt;black veins &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; tentacles?! &lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt; she&amp;rsquo;s glowing???&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned into my worst drawing nightmare. I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;glad&lt;/em&gt; her outfit is so darn easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALSO, LAST NOTE ON HER OUTFIT&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m proud that she&amp;rsquo;s still wearing that necklace.
One of the most jarring characteristics of any squid is the &lt;strong&gt;single wide-open
eye&lt;/strong&gt; and the necklace mimics that &lt;strong&gt;perfectly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;powers-and-abilities&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Powers and Abilities&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heheheheheheheheheheheheheheheh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEY&amp;rsquo;RE A SECRET. &lt;em&gt;(For now&amp;hellip;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll just &lt;strong&gt;have to keep reading to find out what her powers are!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But GUESS WHAT&amp;mdash; You won&amp;rsquo;t have to wait long! In fact, &lt;strong&gt;only until the &lt;em&gt;next page&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OOOOOOOoooooOOOOOOOOooooooOOOOOOOOO!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a good feeling that I&amp;rsquo;ll have page 32 up next weekend, but in case I don&amp;rsquo;t,
I&amp;rsquo;ll still upload a fun post!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m giving myself until the end of November to
get this page done, mostly so that I&amp;rsquo;m not stressing myself out over it. However,
I&amp;rsquo;m certain I won&amp;rsquo;t need that deadline, it&amp;rsquo;s just a safety net and I&amp;rsquo;m already
super close to finishing the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;strong&gt;I appreciate your patience&lt;/strong&gt; in my delay to get this page up. As
mentioned above, Tenti is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; easy to draw and I&amp;rsquo;m getting worn out from
drawing/coloring as much as I did this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So check out the next post next weekend, in case I post the page! &lt;strong&gt;Have a great
weekend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Page (11-03-18)</title>
      <link>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 09:14:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcrice123.github.io/morphic/blog/no-update-11-03-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ballpoint pen drawings of Errie and Vix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-page-today-hope-you-like-sticky-notes&#34;&gt;No page today&amp;mdash;Hope you like sticky notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time this week to work on page 32. Even before
posting the previous page, I felt more confident about getting it done this
coming week, what with Halloween and All Saint&amp;rsquo;s Day among other things to
worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I still have a lot to get done on page 32 in one week. I still
haven&amp;rsquo;t put text on it, not to mention flatting and coloring. &lt;strong&gt;Therefore,
hopefully it will not surprise anyone if I can&amp;rsquo;t finish page 32 on time again.&lt;/strong&gt;
If that happens, I&amp;rsquo;ll post another no-page update and delay page 32&amp;rsquo;s post
another week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; page I&amp;rsquo;ll finish before I take a break from drawing new pages
for a few months.&lt;/strong&gt; The only reason I&amp;rsquo;m trying so hard to post this page and the last
page despite delays is that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about unfinished pages when I&amp;rsquo;m
on break. I apologize for the late/delayed posts recently. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize until
then that I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; needed a break. This year was the first time I ever colored
pages and it was definitely a learning experience on what I can or cannot handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out next week&amp;rsquo;s post for more news about my upcoming break! With a good
schedule this coming week, I should be able to post the next page, &lt;strong&gt;but
we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see!&lt;/strong&gt; If not, I&amp;rsquo;ll still upload some art!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>